<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<questions>
  <question id="G3_NF_3_NF_A_2_1750617594213" grade="3" domain="NF" standard="3.NF.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      In a magical lab, Jordan uses 3/4 of a gallon of potion. How much potion remains if the cauldron holds 1 gallon?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        7/4 gallons
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        1/4 gallons
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        3/4 gallons
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        2/4 gallons
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      Jordan starts with 1 whole gallon of potion in the cauldron. He uses 3/4 of that gallon, so we need to find out how much is left. To do this, we subtract the potion used from the total: 1 - 3/4. Since 1 is the same as 4/4, we can write the subtraction as 4/4 - 3/4. When we subtract the fractions, 4/4 - 3/4 equals 1/4. The answer is 1/4 gallons.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Sun Jun 22 2025 18:39:56 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        842
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      1/4 gallons
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_A_4_1750617469278" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.A.4" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Quinn needs 24 healing herbs for a potion. If he has 6 herbs, how many more does he need to brew the potion?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        23 herbs
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        30 herbs
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        36 herbs
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        18 herbs
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      Quinn needs a total of 24 healing herbs to make his potion, but he only has 6 herbs right now. To find out how many more herbs he needs, we subtract the number of herbs he has from the total number of herbs needed. So, we do the math: 24 - 6 = 18. The answer is 18 herbs.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Sun Jun 22 2025 18:37:51 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        790
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      18 herbs
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NBT_3_NBT_A_2_1750617183956" grade="3" domain="NBT" standard="3.NBT.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Alex needs 45 apples for a potion. He has 27 apples. How many more apples does Alex need to complete his magical brew?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        23 apples
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        18 apples
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        36 apples
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        20 apples
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many more apples Alex needs, we need to subtract the number of apples he already has from the total number he needs. Start with the total number of apples needed, which is 45, and subtract the number of apples Alex already has, which is 27. So, we calculate 45 - 27. First, subtract the ones: 5 - 7. Since 5 is smaller than 7, we need to borrow 1 from the tens place. This makes it 15 - 7, which equals 8. Next, subtract the tens: 4 (after borrowing, it becomes 3) - 2, which equals 1. Putting it all together, Alex needs 18 more apples. The answer is 18 apples.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Sun Jun 22 2025 18:33:08 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        875
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      18 apples
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_C_7_1750617030005" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.C.7" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Blake has 3 crystal vials, each holding 2 fluid ounces of potion. How many fluid ounces of potion does Blake have in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        11 fluid ounces
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        12 fluid ounces
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        6 fluid ounces
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        8 fluid ounces
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many fluid ounces of potion Blake has in total, we need to multiply the number of vials by the amount each vial holds. Blake has 3 vials, and each one holds 2 fluid ounces. So, we multiply 3 (vials) by 2 (fluid ounces per vial): 3 x 2 = 6. The answer is 6 fluid ounces.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Sun Jun 22 2025 18:30:32 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        803
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      6 fluid ounces
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_B_6_1750616897098" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.B.6" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Blake has 24 crystal vials. He divides them equally among 4 cauldrons. How many vials does each cauldron get?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        8 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        11 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        12 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        6 vials
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many vials each cauldron gets, we need to divide the total number of vials by the number of cauldrons. Blake has 24 crystal vials, and he wants to divide them equally among 4 cauldrons. We do this by calculating 24 divided by 4, which equals 6. This means each cauldron gets 6 vials. The answer is 6 vials.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Sun Jun 22 2025 18:28:22 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        819
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      6 vials
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_A_1_1750616609509" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Riley brews a potion with 3 apples every 15 minutes. How many apples does Riley use in 1 hour?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        12 apples
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        17 apples
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        24 apples
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        14 apples
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many apples Riley uses in 1 hour, we need to know how many 15-minute intervals are in 1 hour. Since 1 hour is 60 minutes, we divide 60 by 15, which gives us 4 intervals. Riley uses 3 apples every 15 minutes, so we multiply 3 apples by 4 intervals: 3 x 4 = 12 apples. The answer is 12 apples.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Sun Jun 22 2025 18:23:31 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        795
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      12 apples
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NF_3_NF_A_3_1750616591440" grade="3" domain="NF" standard="3.NF.A.3" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Taylor has 8 crystal vials. She uses 3/8 for a potion. What fraction of the vials are left?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        10/8
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        6/8
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        7/8
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        5/8
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      Taylor starts with 8 crystal vials, and she uses 3 out of those 8 vials for a potion. To find out how many vials are left, we subtract the fraction she used from the total fraction of vials. So, we have 8/8 (the total vials) minus 3/8 (the vials used), which equals 5/8. This means 5 out of the 8 vials are still there. The answer is 5/8.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Sun Jun 22 2025 18:23:15 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        824
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      5/8
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NBT_3_NBT_A_1_1750616236337" grade="3" domain="NBT" standard="3.NBT.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Blake has 47 crystal vials. If he rounds the number of vials to the nearest ten for potion brewing, how many vials does he have?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        40
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        45
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        60
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        50
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To round 47 to the nearest ten, we first look at the digit in the ones place, which is 7. Since 7 is 5 or more, we round up the tens place. So, we increase the 4 in the tens place by 1, making it 5, and change the ones place to 0. The answer is 50.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Sun Jun 22 2025 18:17:19 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        801
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      50
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_A_2_1750616161084" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Taylor has 18 crystal vials of dragon scales. Each potion requires 3 vials. How many potions can Taylor brew?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        6 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        12 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        8 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        11 potions
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many potions Taylor can brew, we need to divide the total number of vials by the number of vials needed for each potion. Taylor has 18 vials, and each potion requires 3 vials. So, we divide 18 by 3. 18 รท 3 = 6 This means Taylor can make 6 potions. The answer is 6 potions.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Sun Jun 22 2025 18:16:03 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        805
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      6 potions
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_B_4_1750616020165" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.B.4" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Taylor measures the height of a crystal vial for a potion. It's 9 inches. Riley's vial is 3 inches taller. How tall is Riley's vial?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        12 inches
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        14 inches
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        17 inches
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        24 inches
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how tall Riley's vial is, we start with the height of Taylor's vial, which is 9 inches. Riley's vial is 3 inches taller than Taylor's vial. So, we need to add 3 inches to 9 inches. When we add 9 + 3, we get 12. The answer is 12 inches.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Sun Jun 22 2025 18:13:43 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        802
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      12 inches
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_A_1_1750615954813" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Morgan starts brewing at 3:15 PM. After mixing healing herbs for 1 hour 45 minutes, what time does Morgan finish the potion?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        7:00 PM
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        3:00 PM
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        10:00 PM
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        5:00 PM
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out when Morgan finishes brewing, we need to add 1 hour and 45 minutes to the starting time of 3:15 PM. First, add 1 hour to 3:15 PM, which makes it 4:15 PM. Next, add 45 minutes to 4:15 PM. Since 15 minutes added to 45 minutes makes 60 minutes, which is 1 hour, the time becomes 5:00 PM. The answer is 5:00 PM.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Sun Jun 22 2025 18:12:37 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        825
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      5:00 PM
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NBT_3_NBT_A_2_1750615673242" grade="3" domain="NBT" standard="3.NBT.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Casey has 57 phoenix feathers. Blake gives her 28 more. How many phoenix feathers does Casey have now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        29 feathers
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        85 feathers
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        170 feathers
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        65 feathers
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many phoenix feathers Casey has now, we need to add the feathers she already has to the feathers Blake gives her. Casey starts with 57 feathers, and Blake gives her 28 more. We add these two numbers together: 57 + 28. First, add the ones place: 7 + 8 equals 15. Write down the 5 and carry over the 1 to the tens place. Next, add the tens place: 5 + 2 equals 7, plus the 1 we carried over equals 8. So, 57 + 28 equals 85. The answer is 85 feathers.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Sun Jun 22 2025 18:07:58 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        840
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      85 feathers
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_A_2_1750615519485" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Taylor brews a potion using 5 crystal vials, each holding 8 fluid ounces. How many fluid ounces of potion does Taylor have in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        45 fluid ounces
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        35 fluid ounces
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        40 fluid ounces
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        80 fluid ounces
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many fluid ounces of potion Taylor has in total, we need to multiply the number of vials by the amount each vial holds. Taylor uses 5 vials, and each vial holds 8 fluid ounces. So, we multiply 5 by 8, which equals 40. The answer is 40 fluid ounces.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Sun Jun 22 2025 18:05:21 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        794
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      40 fluid ounces
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_B_5_1750615458280" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.B.5" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Quinn uses 3 ounces of healing herbs in each potion. If she brews 4 potions, how many ounces of herbs does she use in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        17 ounces
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        14 ounces
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        12 ounces
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        24 ounces
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many ounces of healing herbs Quinn uses in total, we need to multiply the number of ounces used in each potion by the number of potions she brews. Quinn uses 3 ounces of herbs for each potion and she makes 4 potions. So, we multiply 3 ounces by 4 potions: 3 x 4 = 12. The answer is 12 ounces.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Sun Jun 22 2025 18:04:20 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        807
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      12 ounces
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NBT_3_NBT_A_2_1750615452474" grade="3" domain="NBT" standard="3.NBT.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Morgan has 45 healing herbs. Jordan gives her 28 more. How many healing herbs does Morgan have now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        53 healing herbs
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        17 healing herbs
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        146 healing herbs
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        73 healing herbs
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many healing herbs Morgan has now, we need to add the herbs she already had to the ones Jordan gave her. Morgan started with 45 healing herbs, and Jordan gave her 28 more. We add these numbers together: 45 + 28. First, add the ones place: 5 + 8 equals 13. Write down the 3 and carry over the 1. Next, add the tens place: 4 + 2 equals 6, plus the 1 we carried over equals 7. So, 45 + 28 equals 73. The answer is 73 healing herbs.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Sun Jun 22 2025 18:04:15 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        838
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      73 healing herbs
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_D_8_1750615326015" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.D.8" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Alex brews a potion using 12 apples. If each apple weighs 8 ounces, what is the total weight of apples in pounds for the potion?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        11 pounds
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        12 pounds
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        8 pounds
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        6 pounds
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find the total weight of the apples in pounds, we first need to find out how many ounces all the apples weigh together. Since each apple weighs 8 ounces and there are 12 apples, we multiply 12 by 8 to get 96 ounces. Next, we convert ounces to pounds. There are 16 ounces in a pound, so we divide 96 by 16, which equals 6. The answer is 6 pounds.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Sun Jun 22 2025 18:02:09 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        807
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      6 pounds
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_B_3_1750614870900" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.B.3" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Riley brews a potion using 12 apples and 3 ounces of dragon scales. If River uses 8 apples, how many more apples does Riley use than River?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        5 apples
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        6 apples
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        8 apples
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        4 apples
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many more apples Riley uses than River, we start by looking at how many apples each person uses. Riley uses 12 apples, and River uses 8 apples. We subtract the number of apples River uses from the number of apples Riley uses: 12 - 8 = 4. The answer is 4 apples.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Sun Jun 22 2025 17:54:33 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        791
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      4 apples
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NF_3_NF_A_2_1750614725333" grade="3" domain="NF" standard="3.NF.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Taylor has 8 crystal vials. 3 are filled with dragon scales. What fraction of the vials are filled with dragon scales?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        1/8
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        6/8
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        5/8
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        3/8
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out what fraction of the vials are filled with dragon scales, we first look at the total number of vials Taylor has, which is 8. Then, we see that 3 of these vials are filled with dragon scales. To write this as a fraction, we put the number of filled vials, 3, over the total number of vials, 8. So, the fraction of vials filled with dragon scales is 3/8. The answer is 3/8.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Sun Jun 22 2025 17:52:07 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        827
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      3/8
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_C_7_1750614720774" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.C.7" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Alex brews a potion using 3 apples. Each apple weighs 5 ounces. What is the total weight of apples used in ounces?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        17 ounces
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        15 ounces
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        30 ounces
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        20 ounces
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find the total weight of the apples Alex used, we need to multiply the number of apples by the weight of each apple. Alex uses 3 apples, and each apple weighs 5 ounces. So, we calculate 3 apples times 5 ounces per apple, which equals 15 ounces. The answer is 15 ounces.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Sun Jun 22 2025 17:52:02 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        777
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      15 ounces
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_C_5_1750473027570" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.C.5" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Taylor has 3 crystal vials, each holding 8 fluid ounces of potion. How many fluid ounces of potion does Taylor have in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        29 fluid ounces
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        19 fluid ounces
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        24 fluid ounces
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        48 fluid ounces
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many fluid ounces of potion Taylor has in total, we need to multiply the number of vials by the amount each vial holds. Taylor has 3 vials, and each vial holds 8 fluid ounces. So, we multiply 3 by 8, which equals 24. The answer is 24 fluid ounces.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Sat Jun 21 2025 02:30:29 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        790
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      24 fluid ounces
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_B_4_1750473022407" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.B.4" tier="1">
    <stem>
      In the alchemical lab, Riley measures 12 fluid ounces of apple potion. How many 3-ounce vials can Riley fill with the potion?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        2 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        8 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        6 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        4 vials
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many 3-ounce vials Riley can fill with 12 fluid ounces of apple potion, we need to divide 12 by 3. We do this because each vial holds 3 ounces, and we want to see how many groups of 3 ounces fit into 12 ounces. When we divide 12 by 3, we get 4. This means Riley can fill 4 vials with the potion. The answer is 4 vials.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Sat Jun 21 2025 02:30:24 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        813
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      4 vials
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NF_3_NF_A_1_1750473016928" grade="3" domain="NF" standard="3.NF.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Casey has 8 phoenix feathers. She uses 1/4 of them in a potion. How many feathers does she use?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        2 feathers
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        7 feathers
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        1 feathers
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        4 feathers
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many feathers Casey uses, we need to calculate 1/4 of 8. First, we divide 8 by 4 because finding 1/4 means dividing the total into 4 equal parts. When we divide 8 by 4, we get 2. This means Casey uses 2 feathers for her potion. The answer is 2 feathers.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Sat Jun 21 2025 02:30:19 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        791
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      2 feathers
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_G_3_G_A_2_1750472954133" grade="3" domain="G" standard="3.G.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Casey has 8 phoenix feathers. She arranges them in a rectangular pattern with 2 rows. How many feathers are in each row?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        6 feathers
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        4 feathers
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        2 feathers
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        8 feathers
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many feathers are in each row, we need to divide the total number of feathers by the number of rows. Casey has 8 feathers and she arranges them into 2 rows. So, we divide 8 by 2. 8 รท 2 = 4 This means there are 4 feathers in each row. The answer is 4 feathers.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Sat Jun 21 2025 02:29:16 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        789
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      4 feathers
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NBT_3_NBT_A_3_1750472818097" grade="3" domain="NBT" standard="3.NBT.A.3" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Blake needs 4 times as many crystal vials as Alex. If Alex has 7 vials, how many does Blake need for the potion?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        28 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        33 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        56 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        32 vials
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many vials Blake needs, we start by knowing that Blake needs 4 times as many vials as Alex. Alex has 7 vials. We multiply 7 by 4 because Blake needs 4 times more: \(7 \times 4 = 28\). The answer is 28 vials.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Sat Jun 21 2025 02:27:00 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        796
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      28 vials
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_A_2_1750472682509" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Morgan needs 3 quarts of healing herbs for a potion. She has 2 quarts. How many more quarts does she need to gather?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        6 quart
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        1 quart
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        2 quart
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        3 quart
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many more quarts Morgan needs, we start with the total amount she wants, which is 3 quarts. She already has 2 quarts. We subtract the amount she has from the total amount she needs: 3 quarts - 2 quarts = 1 quart. The answer is 1 quart.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Sat Jun 21 2025 02:24:46 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        787
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      1 quart
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NF_3_NF_A_3_1750472678821" grade="3" domain="NF" standard="3.NF.A.3" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Morgan has 3/4 cup of healing herbs. Jordan gives her another 1/4 cup. How much healing herbs does Morgan have now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        6 cup
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        3 cup
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        2 cup
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        1 cup
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how much healing herbs Morgan has now, we need to add the fractions 3/4 and 1/4. First, we look at the denominators, which are the same (4), so we can add the numerators directly. We add 3 (from 3/4) and 1 (from 1/4) to get 4. So, 3/4 + 1/4 = 4/4. Since 4/4 is the same as 1 whole, Morgan now has 1 cup of healing herbs. The answer is 1 cup.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Sat Jun 21 2025 02:24:42 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        844
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      1 cup
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NBT_3_NBT_A_2_1750472617928" grade="3" domain="NBT" standard="3.NBT.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Alex brews a potion using 47 apples. Parker adds 35 more apples. How many apples are in the cauldron now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        82 apples
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        52 apples
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        41 apples
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        164 apples
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many apples are in the cauldron, we need to add the apples Alex used to the apples Parker added. Alex used 47 apples, and Parker added 35 more apples. We add these two numbers together: 47 + 35. First, add the tens: 40 + 30 = 70. Then, add the ones: 7 + 5 = 12. Finally, add the tens and ones together: 70 + 12 = 82. The answer is 82 apples.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Sat Jun 21 2025 02:23:40 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        823
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      82 apples
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_D_8_1750472613288" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.D.8" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Quinn needs 3 pints of healing herbs. Each pint weighs 12 ounces. How many ounces of healing herbs does Quinn need in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        31 ounces
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        41 ounces
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        36 ounces
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        72 ounces
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many ounces of healing herbs Quinn needs, we start by knowing that each pint weighs 12 ounces. Since Quinn needs 3 pints, we multiply 12 ounces by 3. So, 12 ounces per pint times 3 pints equals 36 ounces. The answer is 36 ounces.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Sat Jun 21 2025 02:23:35 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        781
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      36 ounces
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_G_3_G_A_1_1750472602844" grade="3" domain="G" standard="3.G.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Blake arranges 12 crystal vials in a circle for a potion. What shape does the circle of vials form?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        Insufficient information
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        Cannot be determined
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        False
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        Circle
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      When Blake arranges 12 crystal vials in a circle, he places them so that each vial is evenly spaced from the others, forming a round shape. This round shape is called a circle because all the vials are the same distance from the center point. The answer is Circle.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Sat Jun 21 2025 02:23:25 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        758
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      Circle
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_C_6_1750472431697" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.C.6" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Hayden uses 24 phoenix feathers to brew a potion. If each feather is 4 inches long, what is the total length of feathers used in inches?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        48 inches
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        28 inches
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        96 inches
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        192 inches
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find the total length of the feathers, we need to multiply the number of feathers by the length of each feather. Hayden uses 24 feathers, and each one is 4 inches long. So, we calculate 24 times 4, which equals 96. The answer is 96 inches.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Sat Jun 21 2025 02:20:34 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        780
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      96 inches
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_A_1_1750472355037" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      River mixes 3 drams of blue potion with 4 drams of red potion. How many drams of potion does River have in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        9 drams
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        14 drams
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        12 drams
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        7 drams
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many drams of potion River has in total, we need to add the drams of blue potion to the drams of red potion. River has 3 drams of blue potion and 4 drams of red potion. So, we add 3 + 4, which equals 7. The answer is 7 drams.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Sat Jun 21 2025 02:19:17 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        792
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      7 drams
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_B_5_1749708966552" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.B.5" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Meadow brews 3 transformation elixir bottles. Each bottle contains 5 magical drops. How many magical drops are there in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        20 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        30 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        17 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        15 drops
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many magical drops there are in total, we need to multiply the number of bottles by the number of drops in each bottle. Meadow has 3 bottles, and each bottle contains 5 magical drops. So, we multiply 3 (bottles) by 5 (drops per bottle): \[ 3 \times 5 = 15 \] This means there are 15 magical drops in total. The answer is 15 drops.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 06:16:09 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        753
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      15 drops
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_D_8_1749708783191" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.D.8" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Hazel brews 248 potions. She gains 3 alchemical mastery points per potion. How many total mastery points does Hazel earn?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        1488
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        744
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        372
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        251
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many mastery points Hazel earns, we need to multiply the number of potions she brews by the points she gains for each potion. Hazel brews 248 potions, and she gains 3 points for each potion. So, we calculate 248 times 3, which equals 744. The answer is 744.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 06:13:05 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        727
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      744
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_G_3_G_A_2_1749708769581" grade="3" domain="G" standard="3.G.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Willow arranges 12 silver flasks of moonbeam essence in equal rows. How many flasks are in each row if there are 3 rows?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        6 flasks
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        8 flasks
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        2 flasks
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        4 flasks
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many flasks are in each row, we need to divide the total number of flasks by the number of rows. Willow has 12 silver flasks and she arranges them in 3 rows. We can divide 12 by 3 to find out how many flasks are in each row: \[ 12 \div 3 = 4 \] So, there are 4 flasks in each row. The answer is 4 flasks.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 06:12:53 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        770
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      4 flasks
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_C_6_1749708305335" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.C.6" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Willow measures 150 pinches of starflower petal dust for a potion. If she uses 75 pinches, how many pinches are left?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        75 pinches
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        85 pinches
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        225 pinches
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        150 pinches
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many pinches of starflower petal dust are left, we start with the total number of pinches Willow has, which is 150. Then, we subtract the number of pinches she uses, which is 75. So, we calculate 150 minus 75. When we subtract 75 from 150, we get 75. The answer is 75 pinches.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 06:05:08 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        762
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      75 pinches
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NF_3_NF_A_1_1749708124436" grade="3" domain="NF" standard="3.NF.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Luna uses 3 out of 8 grams of powdered unicorn horn for a potion. What fraction of the unicorn horn does she use?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        3/8
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        5/8
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        6/8
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        1/8
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out what fraction of the powdered unicorn horn Luna uses, we need to compare the amount she uses to the total amount she has. Luna uses 3 grams out of a total of 8 grams. We can write this as a fraction, where the top number (numerator) is the amount she uses, which is 3, and the bottom number (denominator) is the total amount, which is 8. So, the fraction of the unicorn horn she uses is 3/8. The answer is 3/8.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 06:02:07 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        828
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      3/8
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NF_3_NF_A_1_1749708025904" grade="3" domain="NF" standard="3.NF.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Elara uses 3 drops of liquid time for a potion. If she has 9 drops in total, what fraction of her drops did she use?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        2/3
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        1/3
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        27/3
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        3/3
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out what fraction of the drops Elara used, we need to compare the number of drops she used to the total number of drops she had. Elara used 3 drops out of the 9 drops she had in total. We can write this as the fraction 3/9. Next, we simplify the fraction 3/9 by dividing both the top number (numerator) and the bottom number (denominator) by their greatest common factor, which is 3. So, 3 divided by 3 is 1, and 9 divided by 3 is 3. This gives us the fraction 1/3. The answer is 1/3.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 06:00:29 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        853
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      1/3
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_B_3_1749708005303" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.B.3" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Clover brews a potion using 40 milliliters of liquid shadow. She adds 15 milliliters more. How many milliliters of liquid shadow are in the potion now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        110 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        55 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        25 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        45 milliliters
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how much liquid shadow is in the potion now, we start with the 40 milliliters Clover used first. Then, she adds 15 more milliliters to it. We add these two amounts together: 40 milliliters + 15 milliliters = 55 milliliters. The answer is 55 milliliters.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 06:00:09 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        814
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      55 milliliters
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_G_3_G_A_1_1749707377344" grade="3" domain="G" standard="3.G.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Sage has 12 glowing phoenix feathers. She arranges them in a rectangle with 3 rows. How many feathers are in each row?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        8 feathers
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        2 feathers
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        4 feathers
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        6 feathers
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many feathers are in each row, we need to divide the total number of feathers by the number of rows. Sage has 12 glowing phoenix feathers, and she arranges them in 3 rows. We divide 12 by 3, which means we need to find out how many times 3 goes into 12. When we divide 12 by 3, we get 4. This means there are 4 feathers in each row. The answer is 4 feathers.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 05:49:40 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        753
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      4 feathers
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_B_3_1749707314199" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.B.3" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Vale earned 250 alchemical mastery points on Monday and 375 on Tuesday. How many points did Vale earn in total over these two days?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        255 points
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        1250 points
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        125 points
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        625 points
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many alchemical mastery points Vale earned in total, we need to add the points from both days together. On Monday, Vale earned 250 points, and on Tuesday, Vale earned 375 points. We add these two numbers: 250 + 375 = 625. The answer is 625 points.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 05:48:36 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        725
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      625 points
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_B_5_1749706859479" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.B.5" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Ocean brews 3 levitation tonic containers. Each container holds 4 magical herbs. How many herbs does Ocean use in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        24 herbs
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        14 herbs
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        17 herbs
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        12 herbs
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many herbs Ocean uses in total, we need to multiply the number of containers by the number of herbs in each container. Ocean has 3 containers, and each one holds 4 herbs. So, we multiply 3 containers by 4 herbs per container: \[ 3 \times 4 = 12 \] This means Ocean uses 12 herbs in total. The answer is 12 herbs.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 05:41:02 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        741
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      12 herbs
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_A_3_1749706686951" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.A.3" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Aspen uses mystical measuring scales to mix 4 dragon scales and 3 phoenix feathers. How many magical ingredients does Aspen have in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        12 ingredients
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        14 ingredients
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        7 ingredients
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        9 ingredients
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many magical ingredients Aspen has, we need to add the number of dragon scales and phoenix feathers together. Aspen has 4 dragon scales and 3 phoenix feathers. We add these numbers: 4 + 3 = 7. The answer is 7 ingredients.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 05:38:09 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        713
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      7 ingredients
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NBT_3_NBT_A_3_1749706345457" grade="3" domain="NBT" standard="3.NBT.A.3" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Ocean needs 215 enchanted mortar and pestles for a potion. If each box holds 10, how many boxes does Ocean need to order?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        44 boxes
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        27 boxes
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        22 boxes
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        17 boxes
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many boxes Ocean needs, we first divide 215 by 10 because each box holds 10 mortar and pestles. When we divide 215 by 10, we get 21 with a remainder of 5. This means Ocean needs 21 full boxes, but since there are 5 extra mortar and pestles, she needs one more box to hold them. The answer is 22 boxes.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 05:32:29 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        751
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      22 boxes
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_A_4_1749706338184" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.A.4" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Wren needs 234 pages to complete a potion recipe. She has 78 pages. How many more pages does she need from ancient grimoires?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        156 pages
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        312 pages
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        78 pages
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        242 pages
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many more pages Wren needs, we need to subtract the pages she already has from the total pages she needs. Wren needs 234 pages in total, and she already has 78 pages. So, we subtract 78 from 234: 234 - 78 = 156 This means Wren needs 156 more pages from ancient grimoires. The answer is 156 pages.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 05:32:21 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        747
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      156 pages
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_B_3_1749706330229" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.B.3" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Wren collected 45 drops of crystallized dragon tears. She gave Willow 15 drops. How many drops does Wren have left for her potion?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        40 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        35 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        60 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        30 drops
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      Wren started with 45 drops of crystallized dragon tears. She gave 15 drops to Willow. To find out how many drops Wren has left, we need to subtract the 15 drops she gave away from the 45 drops she started with. So, we calculate 45 - 15, which equals 30. The answer is 30 drops.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 05:32:15 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        746
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      30 drops
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NBT_3_NBT_A_2_1749706190540" grade="3" domain="NBT" standard="3.NBT.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Clover needs 47 levitation tonic containers. She already brewed 29. How many more containers does she need to brew?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        23
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        20
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        36
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        18
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many more levitation tonic containers Clover needs to brew, we start with the total number she needs, which is 47. Then, we subtract the number she has already brewed, which is 29. So, we do the subtraction: 47 - 29. First, subtract the ones: 7 - 9. Since 7 is smaller than 9, we need to borrow 1 from the tens place. This makes the 7 become 17, and the 4 in the tens place becomes 3. Now, subtract the ones: 17 - 9 = 8. Next, subtract the tens: 3 - 2 = 1. So, Clover needs to brew 18 more containers. The answer is 18.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 05:29:55 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        813
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      18
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NBT_3_NBT_A_3_1749705994720" grade="3" domain="NBT" standard="3.NBT.A.3" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Storm needs 214 arcane flame sources to brew a potion. If each cauldron holds 10 sources, how many cauldrons does Storm need?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        22 cauldrons
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        27 cauldrons
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        17 cauldrons
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        44 cauldrons
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many cauldrons Storm needs, we need to divide the total number of arcane flame sources, which is 214, by the number of sources each cauldron can hold, which is 10. When we divide 214 by 10, we get 21 with a remainder of 4. This means Storm needs 21 full cauldrons, and since there are 4 sources left over, he will need one more cauldron to hold them. The answer is 22 cauldrons.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 05:26:37 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        792
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      22 cauldrons
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_A_4_1749705475099" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.A.4" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Briar needs 24 starflower petals for a potion. She has 8 petals. How many more petals does she need to gather?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        21 petals
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        18 petals
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        32 petals
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        16 petals
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many more petals Briar needs, we start with the total number of petals she wants, which is 24. She already has 8 petals. We need to subtract the petals she has from the total petals needed: 24 - 8. When we do the subtraction, we get 16. The answer is 16 petals.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 05:17:58 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        731
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      16 petals
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_A_1_1749705451779" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Ruby collects 18 glowing phoenix feathers. She needs 3 feathers for each potion. How many potions can Ruby brew?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        8 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        6 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        12 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        11 potions
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many potions Ruby can brew, we need to divide the total number of feathers by the number of feathers needed for each potion. Ruby has 18 feathers, and she needs 3 feathers for each potion. We can divide 18 by 3 to find the answer: \[ 18 \div 3 = 6 \] This means Ruby can make 6 potions. The answer is 6 potions.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 05:17:35 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        744
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      6 potions
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_C_5_1749705387322" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.C.5" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Cedar earns 200 alchemical mastery points for each potion brewed. If Cedar brews 5 potions, how many points does Cedar earn in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        1000 points
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        500 points
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        2000 points
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        205 points
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many points Cedar earns in total, we need to multiply the number of potions brewed by the points earned for each potion. Cedar earns 200 points for each potion and brews 5 potions. So, we calculate 200 times 5, which equals 1000. The answer is 1000 points.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 05:16:29 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        736
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      1000 points
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_B_4_1749705252392" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.B.4" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Storm measures 45 drops of liquid time for a potion. Jasper adds 30 more drops. How many drops of liquid time are in the cauldron now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        15 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        75 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        45 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        150 drops
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many drops of liquid time are in the cauldron now, we need to add the drops Storm and Jasper used. Storm started with 45 drops, and then Jasper added 30 more drops. We add these two numbers together: 45 + 30 = 75. The answer is 75 drops.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 05:14:14 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        773
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      75 drops
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_A_1_1749705054723" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Jasper adds 45 pinches of starflower petal dust to his potion every hour. How many pinches does he use in 3 hours?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        48 pinches
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        42 pinches
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        270 pinches
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        135 pinches
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many pinches of starflower petal dust Jasper uses in 3 hours, we need to multiply the number of pinches he adds each hour by the number of hours. Jasper adds 45 pinches every hour, and he does this for 3 hours. So, we calculate \(45 \times 3 = 135\). The answer is 135 pinches.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 05:10:57 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        757
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      135 pinches
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_A_3_1749705003567" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.A.3" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Vale has 12 distillation tubes. He uses 3 tubes for each potion batch. How many potion batches can Vale make?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        4 potion batches
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        6 potion batches
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        8 potion batches
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        2 potion batches
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many potion batches Vale can make, we need to divide the total number of distillation tubes by the number of tubes used for each batch. Vale has 12 distillation tubes, and he uses 3 tubes for each batch. So, we divide 12 by 3. 12 รท 3 = 4 This means Vale can make 4 potion batches. The answer is 4 potion batches.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 05:10:06 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        743
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      4 potion batches
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_D_8_1749704990440" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.D.8" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Felix has 45 drops of crystallized dragon tears. He uses 15 drops in a potion. How many drops does he have left?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        40 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        30 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        35 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        60 drops
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many drops Felix has left, we start with the total number of drops he had, which is 45. Then, we subtract the 15 drops he used in the potion. So, we do the subtraction: 45 - 15. When we subtract 15 from 45, we get 30. The answer is 30 drops.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 05:09:53 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        737
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      30 drops
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NBT_3_NBT_A_1_1749704894752" grade="3" domain="NBT" standard="3.NBT.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Aspen has 208 starflower petals. She needs to round the number to the nearest ten for her potion. How many petals should she use?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        105
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        210
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        215
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        420
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To round 208 to the nearest ten, we first look at the digit in the ones place, which is 8. Since 8 is 5 or more, we round up the tens digit from 0 to 1. This makes the number 210. The answer is 210.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 05:08:17 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        718
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      210
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_A_2_1749704367780" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Felix has 15 enchanted stirring rods. He needs 3 rods to brew one potion. How many potions can Felix brew with his rods?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        10 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        3 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        7 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        5 potions
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many potions Felix can brew, we need to divide the total number of rods by the number of rods needed for one potion. Felix has 15 rods, and he needs 3 rods for each potion. So, we divide 15 by 3. 15 รท 3 = 5 This means Felix can brew 5 potions. The answer is 5 potions.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 04:59:31 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        746
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      5 potions
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_C_7_1749703776703" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.C.7" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Sage needs 4 cauldrons of moonbeam essence. Each cauldron holds 6 milliliters. How many milliliters does Sage need in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        24 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        48 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        19 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        29 milliliters
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many milliliters of moonbeam essence Sage needs in total, we need to multiply the number of cauldrons by the amount each cauldron holds. Sage needs 4 cauldrons, and each cauldron holds 6 milliliters. So, we multiply 4 by 6, which equals 24. The answer is 24 milliliters.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 04:49:38 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        822
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      24 milliliters
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_C_7_1749703768587" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.C.7" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Cedar needs 243 drops of liquid time for a potion. If each batch contains 27 drops, how many batches does Cedar need to brew?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        18 batches
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        11 batches
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        9 batches
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        14 batches
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many batches Cedar needs, we need to divide the total number of drops, 243, by the number of drops in each batch, which is 27. We can do this by asking, "How many times does 27 fit into 243?" When we divide 243 by 27, we get 9. This means Cedar needs to make 9 batches to have enough drops for the potion. The answer is 9 batches.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 04:49:32 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        794
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      9 batches
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_D_8_1749703574897" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.D.8" tier="1">
    <stem>
      River brews a potion using 350 units of magical energy. Ocean adds 150 more. How many units of magical energy are in the potion now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        1000 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        500 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        350 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        250 units
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many units of magical energy are in the potion now, we need to add the units of energy River and Ocean used. River started with 350 units of magical energy, and Ocean added 150 more units. We add these two numbers together: 350 + 150 = 500. The answer is 500 units.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 04:46:18 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        731
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      500 units
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_B_4_1749703445376" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.B.4" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Elara needs 150 grams of powdered unicorn horn for a potion. She has 60 grams. How many more grams does she need to gather?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        45 grams
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        150 grams
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        90 grams
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        180 grams
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many more grams Elara needs, we start with the total amount she needs, which is 150 grams. She already has 60 grams. We need to subtract the amount she has from the total amount needed. So, we do the subtraction: 150 grams - 60 grams = 90 grams. The answer is 90 grams.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 04:44:08 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        792
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      90 grams
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_C_6_1749703366183" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.C.6" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Hazel brews a potion using 35 drops of liquid time. She adds 15 more drops. How many drops of liquid time are in the potion now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        55 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        45 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        50 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        100 drops
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many drops of liquid time are in the potion now, we need to add the drops Hazel started with to the drops she added. Hazel started with 35 drops of liquid time and then added 15 more drops. We add these numbers together: 35 + 15 = 50. The answer is 50 drops.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 04:42:49 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        775
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      50 drops
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_G_3_G_A_2_1749703230194" grade="3" domain="G" standard="3.G.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Rowan arranges 24 vials of liquid shadow into equal rows in a cauldron. How many vials are in each row if there are 4 rows?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        6 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        11 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        12 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        8 vials
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many vials are in each row, we need to divide the total number of vials by the number of rows. Rowan has 24 vials and wants to arrange them into 4 equal rows. We divide 24 by 4, which is 24 รท 4 = 6. The answer is 6 vials.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 04:40:33 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        745
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      6 vials
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_C_5_1749702973230" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.C.5" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Luna brews a potion using 3 cauldrons. Each cauldron holds 150 units of magical energy. How many units of magical energy are used in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        147 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        225 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        900 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        450 units
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many units of magical energy Luna uses in total, we need to add up the energy from all three cauldrons. Each cauldron holds 150 units of magical energy. So, we multiply the number of cauldrons (3) by the units of energy each one holds (150). The multiplication looks like this: 3 x 150 = 450. The answer is 450 units.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 04:36:17 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        764
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      450 units
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NF_3_NF_A_2_1749702588537" grade="3" domain="NF" standard="3.NF.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Cedar brews 500 milliliters of concentrated lightning. He uses 3/5 of it. How many milliliters remain?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        400 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        200 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        507 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        100 milliliters
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many milliliters of concentrated lightning Cedar has left, we first need to calculate how much he used. Cedar used 3/5 of 500 milliliters. To find 3/5 of 500, multiply 500 by 3/5: \[ 500 \times \frac{3}{5} = 300. \] This means Cedar used 300 milliliters. To find out how much is left, subtract 300 from 500: \[ 500 - 300 = 200. \] The answer is 200 milliliters.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 04:29:52 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        846
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      200 milliliters
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NBT_3_NBT_A_2_1749702583765" grade="3" domain="NBT" standard="3.NBT.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Wren brews 47 transformation elixir bottles. Willow brews 36 more. How many bottles do they have in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        166 bottles
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        11 bottles
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        83 bottles
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        53 bottles
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many bottles Wren and Willow have together, we need to add the number of bottles each brewed. Wren brewed 47 bottles, and Willow brewed 36 more bottles. We add these two numbers together: 47 + 36 = 83 So, Wren and Willow have a total of 83 bottles. The answer is 83 bottles.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 04:29:46 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        740
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      83 bottles
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_A_3_1749702326559" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.A.3" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Iris has 9 self-heating cauldrons. She uses 3 cauldrons for each potion. How many potions can Iris brew?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        6 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        3 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        5 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        1 potions
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many potions Iris can brew, we need to divide the total number of cauldrons by the number of cauldrons used for each potion. Iris has 9 cauldrons, and she uses 3 cauldrons for each potion. So, we divide 9 by 3: \[ 9 \div 3 = 3 \] This means Iris can brew 3 potions. The answer is 3 potions.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 04:25:29 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        779
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      3 potions
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_G_3_G_A_1_1749702089349" grade="3" domain="G" standard="3.G.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Luna has a cauldron with 60 milliliters of liquid shadow. She adds another 30 milliliters. How much liquid shadow is in the cauldron now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        45 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        90 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        60 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        180 milliliters
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how much liquid shadow is in the cauldron now, we need to add the amount Luna already has to the amount she adds. Luna starts with 60 milliliters of liquid shadow and then adds 30 milliliters. We add these two numbers together: 60 + 30 = 90. The answer is 90 milliliters.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 04:21:32 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        810
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      90 milliliters
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_A_2_1749701956718" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Aurora needs 15 bottles of concentrated lightning. If each potion requires 3 bottles, how many potions can she brew?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        7 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        10 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        3 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        5 potions
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many potions Aurora can brew, we need to divide the total number of bottles she has by the number of bottles needed for each potion. Aurora has 15 bottles of concentrated lightning, and each potion requires 3 bottles. We divide 15 by 3 to find the number of potions: \[ 15 \div 3 = 5 \] This means Aurora can make 5 potions. The answer is 5 potions.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 04:19:20 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        753
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      5 potions
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_C_7_1749701938297" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.C.7" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Ember has 300 milliliters of concentrated lightning. She uses 150 milliliters in a potion. How much is left?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        300 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        150 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        450 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        75 milliliters
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how much concentrated lightning Ember has left, we start with the amount she had at first, which is 300 milliliters. Then, we subtract the 150 milliliters she used in the potion. So, we do the math: 300 milliliters - 150 milliliters = 150 milliliters. The answer is 150 milliliters.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 04:19:01 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        797
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      150 milliliters
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_D_8_1749701528695" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.D.8" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Aurora earns 150 alchemical mastery points each time she brews a potion. How many points does she earn after brewing 4 potions?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        1200 points
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        600 points
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        750 points
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        450 points
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many points Aurora earns after brewing 4 potions, we need to multiply the points she earns for one potion by the number of potions. Aurora earns 150 points for each potion, so we multiply 150 by 4. The multiplication looks like this: 150 x 4 = 600. The answer is 600 points.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 04:12:12 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        735
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      600 points
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NF_3_NF_A_1_1749700897228" grade="3" domain="NF" standard="3.NF.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Finn has 15 milliliters of moonbeam essence. He uses 1/3 for a potion. How many milliliters does he use?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        10 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        5 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        3 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        7 milliliters
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many milliliters of moonbeam essence Finn uses, we need to calculate 1/3 of 15 milliliters. First, divide 15 by 3, because 1/3 means we are splitting 15 into 3 equal parts. When we divide 15 by 3, we get 5. So, Finn uses 5 milliliters of moonbeam essence for his potion. The answer is 5 milliliters.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 04:01:40 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        827
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      5 milliliters
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_A_2_1749700891747" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      River has 24 vials of liquid shadow. If each potion requires 4 vials, how many potions can River brew?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        8 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        12 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        6 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        11 potions
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many potions River can brew, we need to divide the total number of vials by the number of vials needed for each potion. River has 24 vials, and each potion requires 4 vials. So, we divide 24 by 4. 24 รท 4 = 6 This means River can make 6 potions. The answer is 6 potions.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 04:01:34 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        748
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      6 potions
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_B_6_1749700763550" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.B.6" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Finn needs 18 arcane flame sources to brew a potion. If each spell requires 3 sources, how many spells can Finn cast?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        6 spells
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        12 spells
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        8 spells
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        11 spells
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many spells Finn can cast, we need to divide the total number of arcane flame sources by the number of sources each spell requires. Finn has 18 arcane flame sources, and each spell needs 3 sources. So, we divide 18 by 3: \[ 18 \div 3 = 6 \] This means Finn can cast 6 spells. The answer is 6 spells.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 03:59:26 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        746
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      6 spells
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_C_7_1749700448423" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.C.7" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Willow needs 36 grams of powdered unicorn horn for a potion. If she uses 4 grams per potion, how many potions can she brew?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        14 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        9 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        18 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        11 potions
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many potions Willow can brew, we need to divide the total amount of powdered unicorn horn by the amount needed for each potion. Willow has 36 grams of powdered unicorn horn and uses 4 grams for each potion. We divide 36 by 4, which equals 9. This means Willow can make 9 potions. The answer is 9 potions.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 03:54:12 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        801
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      9 potions
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_D_8_1749700445197" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.D.8" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Ivy brews a potion with 247 units of magical energy. She adds 153 more units. How many units of magical energy does the potion have now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        800 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        400 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        250 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        200 units
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many units of magical energy Ivy's potion has now, we need to add the units she started with to the units she added. Ivy started with 247 units and added 153 more units. We add these numbers together: 247 + 153 = 400. The answer is 400 units.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 03:54:08 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        733
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      400 units
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_B_6_1749700442655" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.B.6" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Luna has 12 enchanted mortar and pestles. She shares them equally among 3 cauldrons. How many mortar and pestles does each cauldron get?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        6
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        4
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        2
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        8
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many enchanted mortar and pestles each cauldron gets, we need to divide the 12 mortar and pestles equally among the 3 cauldrons. We do this by dividing 12 by 3. When we divide 12 by 3, we get 4 because 3 times 4 equals 12. The answer is 4.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 03:54:05 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        754
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      4
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_A_2_1749700269246" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Felix needs 150 grams of powdered unicorn horn for a potion. He has 90 grams. How many more grams does he need?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        30 grams
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        120 grams
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        60 grams
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        150 grams
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many more grams Felix needs, we start by looking at how much he already has, which is 90 grams. We know he needs a total of 150 grams. To find the difference, we subtract the amount he has from the total amount he needs: 150 grams - 90 grams = 60 grams. The answer is 60 grams.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 03:51:11 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        785
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      60 grams
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NF_3_NF_A_2_1749700265929" grade="3" domain="NF" standard="3.NF.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Willow gains 3/4 of her alchemical mastery points by brewing potions. If she has 1200 points, how many points are from brewing?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        450 points
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        905 points
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        1800 points
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        900 points
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many of Willow's points come from brewing potions, we need to calculate 3/4 of her total points, which is 1200. First, divide 1200 by 4 to find 1/4 of the points: 1200 รท 4 = 300. Then, multiply 300 by 3 to find 3/4 of the points: 300 ร 3 = 900. The answer is 900 points.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 03:51:09 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        767
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      900 points
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_G_3_G_A_2_1749700203927" grade="3" domain="G" standard="3.G.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Hazel uses 12 enchanted stirring rods to brew potions. She arranges them into equal rows in her cauldron. How many rods are in each row if there are 3 rows?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        6 rods
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        4 rods
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        2 rods
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        8 rods
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many rods are in each row, we need to divide the total number of rods by the number of rows. Hazel has 12 rods and she arranges them into 3 equal rows. We divide 12 by 3, which is written as 12 รท 3. When we divide 12 by 3, we get 4. This means there are 4 rods in each row. The answer is 4 rods.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 03:50:07 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        767
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      4 rods
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_C_6_1749700139094" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.C.6" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Rowan pours 80 milliliters of liquid shadow into a cauldron, then adds 40 milliliters more. How many milliliters of liquid shadow are in the cauldron now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        80 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        60 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        120 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        240 milliliters
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how much liquid shadow is in the cauldron, we need to add the amounts Rowan poured. First, he poured 80 milliliters, and then he added 40 milliliters more. We add these two amounts together: 80 + 40 = 120. The answer is 120 milliliters.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 03:49:03 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        815
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      120 milliliters
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_A_1_1749700004207" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Ember has 24 silver flasks of moonbeam essence. She divides them equally among 3 cauldrons. How many flasks does each cauldron receive?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        10 flasks
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        13 flasks
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        8 flasks
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        16 flasks
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many flasks each cauldron receives, we need to divide the total number of flasks by the number of cauldrons. Ember has 24 silver flasks, and she is dividing them equally among 3 cauldrons. We do this by calculating 24 divided by 3, which equals 8. The answer is 8 flasks.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 03:46:47 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        764
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      8 flasks
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_B_4_1749699831454" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.B.4" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Ocean uses 25 milliliters of moonbeam essence in a potion. Ruby uses 15 milliliters. How much more essence does Ocean use than Ruby?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        15 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        10 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        20 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        12 milliliters
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how much more moonbeam essence Ocean uses than Ruby, we need to subtract the amount Ruby uses from the amount Ocean uses. Ocean uses 25 milliliters, and Ruby uses 15 milliliters. We do the subtraction: 25 - 15 = 10. The answer is 10 milliliters.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 03:43:54 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        800
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      10 milliliters
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_G_3_G_A_1_1749699764436" grade="3" domain="G" standard="3.G.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Finn adds 3 pinches of starflower petal dust to each of 4 cauldrons. How many pinches does he use in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        24 pinches
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        12 pinches
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        17 pinches
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        14 pinches
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many pinches of starflower petal dust Finn uses in total, we need to multiply the number of pinches he adds to each cauldron by the number of cauldrons. Finn adds 3 pinches to each of the 4 cauldrons. So, we calculate 3 pinches times 4 cauldrons, which equals 12 pinches. The answer is 12 pinches.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 03:42:48 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        766
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      12 pinches
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_A_2_1749699703321" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Aurora needs 45 milliliters of moonbeam essence for a potion. She has 30 milliliters. How much more does she need to brew the potion?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        20 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        17 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        15 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        30 milliliters
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how much more moonbeam essence Aurora needs, we start by looking at how much she already has, which is 30 milliliters. She needs a total of 45 milliliters for her potion. We can find out how much more she needs by subtracting the amount she has from the total amount needed: 45 milliliters - 30 milliliters = 15 milliliters. The answer is 15 milliliters.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 03:41:47 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        830
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      15 milliliters
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_B_3_1749699508099" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.B.3" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Briar uses a line plot to show pinches of starflower petal dust used daily: 5, 7, 5, 8, 7, 5. How many days did Briar use 5 pinches?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        6 days
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        1 days
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        5 days
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        3 days
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many days Briar used 5 pinches of starflower petal dust, we need to count how many times the number 5 appears in the list. The numbers are 5, 7, 5, 8, 7, and 5. If we look closely, we see the number 5 appears three times. The answer is 3 days.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 03:38:30 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        795
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      3 days
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NBT_3_NBT_A_1_1749699475530" grade="3" domain="NBT" standard="3.NBT.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Iris needs 207 ancient grimoires for a potion. Round the number of grimoires to the nearest ten. How many grimoires does she need?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        215
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        420
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        210
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        105
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To round 207 to the nearest ten, we first look at the digit in the ones place, which is 7. Since 7 is 5 or more, we round the tens place up from 0 to 1. This means 207 rounds up to 210. The answer is 210.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 03:37:58 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        723
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      210
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_B_6_1749699146506" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.B.6" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Elara uses 24 crystal essence extractors to brew potions. If each extractor holds 3 magical crystals, how many crystals does she have in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        72 crystals
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        36 crystals
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        27 crystals
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        144 crystals
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many magical crystals Elara has in total, we need to multiply the number of extractors by the number of crystals each one holds. Elara has 24 extractors, and each one holds 3 crystals. So, we multiply 24 by 3: \[ 24 \times 3 = 72 \] This means Elara has 72 magical crystals in total. The answer is 72 crystals.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 03:32:30 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        760
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      72 crystals
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NF_3_NF_A_3_1749699138716" grade="3" domain="NF" standard="3.NF.A.3" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Hazel brews a potion using 3/4 of 60 milliliters of liquid shadow. How many milliliters does she use?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        40 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        50 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        90 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        45 milliliters
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how much liquid shadow Hazel uses, we need to calculate 3/4 of 60 milliliters. First, divide 60 by 4, which equals 15. This tells us how much 1/4 of 60 milliliters is. Next, multiply 15 by 3, because Hazel uses 3 parts out of 4. So, 15 times 3 equals 45. The answer is 45 milliliters.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 03:32:22 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        822
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      45 milliliters
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_C_7_1749698980541" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.C.7" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Ruby uses 150 grams of powdered unicorn horn to brew a potion. Meadow uses 50 grams less. How many grams does Meadow use?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        110 grams
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        200 grams
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        100 grams
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        50 grams
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many grams of powdered unicorn horn Meadow uses, we start with the amount Ruby uses, which is 150 grams. Meadow uses 50 grams less than Ruby. So, we subtract 50 grams from 150 grams. The math looks like this: 150 grams - 50 grams = 100 grams. The answer is 100 grams.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 03:29:43 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        787
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      100 grams
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_A_2_1749698846922" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Aspen brews a potion using 250 units of magical energy. Cedar adds 150 more units. How many units of magical energy are in the potion now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        250 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        400 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        200 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        800 units
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many units of magical energy are in the potion now, we need to add the units that Aspen and Cedar used together. Aspen used 250 units, and Cedar added 150 more units. We add these two numbers: 250 + 150 = 400. The answer is 400 units.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 03:27:31 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        730
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      400 units
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_B_4_1749698777232" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.B.4" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Meadow adds 30 grams of ethereal powder to her potion. Later, she adds 25 grams more. How many grams of ethereal powder are in the potion now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        35 grams
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        5 grams
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        110 grams
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        55 grams
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many grams of ethereal powder are in the potion now, we need to add the two amounts Meadow used. First, she added 30 grams of powder. Then, she added 25 grams more. We add these two numbers together: 30 + 25 = 55. The answer is 55 grams.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 03:26:20 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        794
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      55 grams
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_C_6_1749698706912" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.C.6" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Ivy measures 60 grams of ethereal powder for a potion. Later, she adds 15 grams. How much ethereal powder does Ivy have now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        65 grams
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        45 grams
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        150 grams
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        75 grams
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how much ethereal powder Ivy has now, we need to add the amount she started with to the amount she added. Ivy started with 60 grams of ethereal powder. Then, she added 15 grams more. We add these two numbers together: 60 grams + 15 grams = 75 grams. The answer is 75 grams.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 03:25:09 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        791
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      75 grams
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NBT_3_NBT_A_3_1749698668014" grade="3" domain="NBT" standard="3.NBT.A.3" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Meadow uses 213 crystal essence extractors to brew potions. If she rounds to the nearest ten, how many extractors does she have?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        420
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        215
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        105
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        210
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To round 213 to the nearest ten, we first look at the digit in the ones place, which is 3. Since 3 is less than 5, we round down. This means we keep the tens digit the same and change the ones digit to 0. So, 213 rounded to the nearest ten is 210. The answer is 210.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 03:24:31 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        737
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      210
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NF_3_NF_A_2_1749698531507" grade="3" domain="NF" standard="3.NF.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Sage brews a potion using 3/4 of a cauldron's magical energy. If the cauldron holds 400 units, how many units of magical energy does Sage use?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        300 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        150 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        305 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        600 units
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how much magical energy Sage uses, we need to calculate 3/4 of the cauldron's total energy, which is 400 units. First, divide 400 by 4 to find 1/4 of the energy: 400 รท 4 = 100 units. Then, multiply 100 units by 3 to find 3/4 of the energy: 100 ร 3 = 300 units. The answer is 300 units.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 03:22:14 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        781
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      300 units
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_G_3_G_A_2_1749698519591" grade="3" domain="G" standard="3.G.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Ivy has 24 bottles of concentrated lightning. She arranges them equally into 4 cauldrons. How many bottles are in each cauldron?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        11 bottles
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        6 bottles
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        8 bottles
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        12 bottles
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many bottles Ivy puts in each cauldron, we need to divide the total number of bottles by the number of cauldrons. Ivy has 24 bottles, and she wants to put them equally into 4 cauldrons. We divide 24 by 4, which is written as \(24 \div 4\). When we do the division, we find that 24 divided by 4 equals 6. The answer is 6 bottles.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 03:22:02 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        762
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      6 bottles
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_B_5_1749698514708" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.B.5" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Storm brews 3 invisibility draught flasks daily. How many flasks does Storm have after 4 days of brewing in the alchemical laboratory?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        24 flasks
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        14 flasks
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        12 flasks
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        17 flasks
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many flasks Storm has after 4 days, we need to multiply the number of flasks brewed each day by the number of days. Storm brews 3 flasks each day, so we calculate 3 flasks times 4 days. This is 3 x 4 = 12. The answer is 12 flasks.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 03:21:57 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        752
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      12 flasks
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_A_4_1749698362725" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.A.4" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Clover has 18 healing potion vials. She divides them equally among 3 cauldrons. How many vials does each cauldron get?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        11 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        6 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        8 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        12 vials
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many healing potion vials each cauldron gets, we need to divide the total number of vials by the number of cauldrons. Clover has 18 vials and she is dividing them equally among 3 cauldrons. We can do this by dividing 18 by 3. When we divide 18 by 3, we get 6. This means each cauldron gets 6 vials. The answer is 6 vials.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 03:19:25 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        771
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      6 vials
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_A_2_1749698358840" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Iris needs 450 milliliters of concentrated lightning for a potion. She already has 275 milliliters. How much more does she need to gather?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        180 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        350 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        175 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        455 milliliters
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how much more concentrated lightning Iris needs, we need to subtract the amount she already has from the total amount she needs. Iris needs 450 milliliters in total and she already has 275 milliliters. So, we do the subtraction: 450 milliliters - 275 milliliters = 175 milliliters. The answer is 175 milliliters.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 03:19:22 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        809
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      175 milliliters
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_C_7_1749698355851" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.C.7" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Jasper brews a potion with 15 milliliters of moonbeam essence. He adds 10 more milliliters. How many milliliters of moonbeam essence does he have now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        50 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        20 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        30 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        25 milliliters
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how much moonbeam essence Jasper has now, we need to add the amount he started with to the amount he added. Jasper started with 15 milliliters of moonbeam essence and then added 10 more milliliters. We add these two amounts together: 15 + 10 = 25. The answer is 25 milliliters.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 03:19:18 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        820
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      25 milliliters
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NBT_3_NBT_A_2_1749698094736" grade="3" domain="NBT" standard="3.NBT.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Briar brews 23 invisibility draught flasks. Rowan adds 15 more. How many flasks do they have in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        33 flasks
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        43 flasks
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        38 flasks
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        76 flasks
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many flasks Briar and Rowan have together, we need to add the number of flasks each of them brewed. Briar brewed 23 flasks, and Rowan added 15 more. We add these numbers together: 23 + 15. First, add the tens: 20 + 10 = 30. Then, add the ones: 3 + 5 = 8. Finally, add the tens and ones together: 30 + 8 = 38. The answer is 38 flasks.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 03:14:57 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        788
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      38 flasks
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_G_3_G_A_1_1749698086237" grade="3" domain="G" standard="3.G.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Cedar needs 60 grams of ethereal powder for a potion. If he divides it equally into 3 cauldrons, how many grams does each cauldron get?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        40 grams
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        22 grams
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        20 grams
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        25 grams
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many grams of ethereal powder each cauldron gets, we need to divide the total amount of powder by the number of cauldrons. Cedar has 60 grams of powder, and he wants to divide it equally into 3 cauldrons. We do this by dividing 60 by 3. So, 60 รท 3 = 20. This means each cauldron will get 20 grams of ethereal powder. The answer is 20 grams.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 03:14:49 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        829
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      20 grams
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_A_1_1749697693111" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Jasper needs 3 cauldrons of potion. Each cauldron requires 15 grams of ethereal powder. How many grams does Jasper need in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        45 grams
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        50 grams
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        90 grams
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        40 grams
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many grams of ethereal powder Jasper needs in total, we need to multiply the number of cauldrons by the amount of powder each cauldron requires. Jasper needs 3 cauldrons, and each cauldron requires 15 grams of powder. So, we calculate 3 times 15, which equals 45. The answer is 45 grams.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 03:08:16 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        804
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      45 grams
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_C_5_1749697450939" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.C.5" tier="1">
    <stem>
      In the alchemical lab, Finn pours 250 milliliters of concentrated lightning into a cauldron. How much more is needed to reach 1 liter?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        1500 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        375 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        750 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        251 milliliters
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how much more is needed to reach 1 liter, we first need to know that 1 liter is the same as 1,000 milliliters. Finn has already poured 250 milliliters into the cauldron. We subtract 250 milliliters from 1,000 milliliters to find out how much more is needed: 1,000 - 250 = 750. The answer is 750 milliliters.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 03:04:13 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        823
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      750 milliliters
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_C_5_1749697447995" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.C.5" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Sage has 45 drops of crystallized dragon tears. If he divides them equally into 5 cauldrons, how many drops are in each cauldron?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        14 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        11 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        18 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        9 drops
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many drops of crystallized dragon tears Sage puts in each cauldron, we need to divide the total number of drops by the number of cauldrons. Sage has 45 drops and he wants to divide them equally into 5 cauldrons. We do this by dividing 45 by 5. When we divide 45 by 5, we get 9. This means each cauldron will have 9 drops. The answer is 9 drops.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 03:04:10 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        779
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      9 drops
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NBT_3_NBT_A_1_1749697373186" grade="3" domain="NBT" standard="3.NBT.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Vale has 209 healing potion vials. If he rounds to the nearest ten, how many vials does he have?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        420
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        215
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        105
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        210
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To round 209 to the nearest ten, first look at the digit in the ones place, which is 9. Since 9 is 5 or more, we round up the digit in the tens place, which is 0, to the next number, making it 1. So, 209 rounded to the nearest ten is 210. The answer is 210.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 03:02:55 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        729
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      210
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NF_3_NF_A_3_1749697365842" grade="3" domain="NF" standard="3.NF.A.3" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Ivy uses 3/4 pinches of starflower petal dust. Wren uses 1/4 pinch. How much more pinches does Ivy use than Wren?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        2/2 pinch
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        12/2 pinch
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        3/2 pinch
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        1/2 pinch
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how much more pinches Ivy uses than Wren, we need to subtract the amount Wren uses from the amount Ivy uses. Ivy uses 3/4 pinches, and Wren uses 1/4 pinch. We subtract 1/4 from 3/4, which is 3/4 - 1/4 = 2/4. We can simplify 2/4 to 1/2 because both the numerator and the denominator can be divided by 2. The answer is 1/2 pinch.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 03:02:50 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        807
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      1/2 pinch
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_A_1_1749697058028" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Ruby needs 90 milliliters of liquid shadow. She has 50 milliliters. How many more milliliters does she need to brew her potion?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        80 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        40 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        35 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        45 milliliters
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      Ruby needs a total of 90 milliliters of liquid shadow for her potion. She already has 50 milliliters. To find out how much more she needs, we subtract the amount she has from the total amount needed: 90 milliliters - 50 milliliters = 40 milliliters. The answer is 40 milliliters.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 02:57:40 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        804
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      40 milliliters
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_A_1_1749697042774" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Ember adds 25 grams of ethereal powder to a potion at 3:00 PM and 30 grams at 3:30 PM. How many grams in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        75 grams
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        61 grams
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        55 grams
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        110 grams
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many grams of ethereal powder Ember added in total, we need to add the two amounts together. First, Ember added 25 grams at 3:00 PM. Then, she added 30 grams at 3:30 PM. We add these two numbers: 25 grams + 30 grams = 55 grams. The answer is 55 grams.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 02:57:25 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        802
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      55 grams
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_D_8_1749696971169" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.D.8" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Rowan brews a potion with 246 milliliters of concentrated lightning. He uses 87 milliliters. How much is left in the cauldron?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        318 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        169 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        333 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        159 milliliters
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how much concentrated lightning is left in the cauldron, we need to subtract the amount Rowan used from the total amount he started with. Rowan started with 246 milliliters and used 87 milliliters. So, we calculate 246 minus 87. First, subtract the ones: 6 minus 7. Since 6 is smaller than 7, we need to borrow from the tens place. Change the 4 in the tens place to a 3, and the 6 becomes 16. Now, 16 minus 7 equals 9. Next, subtract the tens: 3 minus 8. Again, we need to borrow, so change the 2 in the hundreds place to a 1, and the 3 becomes 13. Now, 13 minus 8 equals 5. Finally, subtract the hundreds: 1 minus 0 equals 1. So, 246 minus 87 equals 159. The answer is 159 milliliters.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 02:56:15 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        940
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      159 milliliters
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NF_3_NF_A_3_1749696965403" grade="3" domain="NF" standard="3.NF.A.3" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Rowan has 15 drops of crystallized dragon tears. Vale gives him 10 more. What fraction of the total drops are from Vale?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        \(\frac{2}{5}\)
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        \(\frac{1}{5}\)
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        \(\frac{3}{5}\)
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        \(\frac{4}{5}\)
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      First, we need to find the total number of drops Rowan has after Vale gives him more. Rowan starts with 15 drops, and Vale gives him 10 more, so we add 15 and 10 to get 25 drops in total. Next, we find out what fraction of these 25 drops came from Vale. Vale gave Rowan 10 drops, so we write this as a fraction: \(\frac{10}{25}\). To simplify \(\frac{10}{25}\), we divide both the top number (numerator) and the bottom number (denominator) by 5, which gives us \(\frac{2}{5}\). The answer is \(\frac{2}{5}\).
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 02:56:09 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        830
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      \(\frac{2}{5}\)
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NF_3_NF_A_2_1749693496440" grade="3" domain="NF" standard="3.NF.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      87 + 45 = ?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        132
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        137
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        264
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        66
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      87 + 45 = 132
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:58:16 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        0
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      132
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_C_6_1749693457726" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.C.6" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Wren measures 150 grams of powdered unicorn horn for a potion. If she uses 50 grams, how much is left?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        200 grams
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        110 grams
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        100 grams
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        50 grams
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how much powdered unicorn horn Wren has left, we start with the amount she measured, which is 150 grams. She uses 50 grams for the potion. We need to subtract the 50 grams she used from the 150 grams she started with. So, we do the math: 150 grams - 50 grams = 100 grams. The answer is 100 grams.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:57:41 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        792
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      100 grams
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NBT_3_NBT_A_1_1749693190132" grade="3" domain="NBT" standard="3.NBT.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Meadow has 38 invisibility draught flasks. She brews 7 more. How many flasks does Meadow have now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        50 flasks
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        40 flasks
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        90 flasks
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        45 flasks
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many invisibility draught flasks Meadow has now, we need to add the 7 new flasks she brewed to the 38 flasks she already had. We do this by adding the numbers: 38 + 7. First, add the ones place: 8 + 7 equals 15. Write down the 5 and carry over the 1 to the tens place. Then, add the tens place: 3 + 1 equals 4. So, 38 + 7 equals 45. The answer is 45 flasks.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:53:13 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        789
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      45 flasks
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NF_3_NF_A_2_1749693070192" grade="3" domain="NF" standard="3.NF.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Finn uses 8 out of 12 enchanted mortar and pestles to grind ingredients for a potion. What fraction of the mortar and pestles does Finn use?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        4/3
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        2/3
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        1/3
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        7/3
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find the fraction of enchanted mortar and pestles Finn uses, we start by looking at the total number of mortar and pestles, which is 12. Finn uses 8 of them. To write this as a fraction, we put the number Finn uses (8) over the total number (12), giving us the fraction 8/12. We can simplify this fraction by dividing both the top number (numerator) and the bottom number (denominator) by their greatest common factor, which is 4. So, 8 divided by 4 is 2, and 12 divided by 4 is 3. This simplifies the fraction to 2/3. The answer is 2/3.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:51:14 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        820
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      2/3
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NBT_3_NBT_A_2_1749692937244" grade="3" domain="NBT" standard="3.NBT.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Storm has 27 levitation tonic containers. Jasper gives him 19 more. How many levitation tonic containers does Storm have now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        51
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        46
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        41
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        92
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many levitation tonic containers Storm has now, we need to add the number of containers he already has to the number Jasper gives him. Storm starts with 27 containers, and Jasper gives him 19 more. We add these numbers together: 27 + 19. First, add the ones place: 7 + 9 equals 16. Write down the 6 and carry over the 1 to the tens place. Next, add the tens place: 2 + 1 equals 3, and don't forget to add the 1 we carried over, which makes it 4. So, the tens place is 4. Putting it all together, Storm now has 46 levitation tonic containers. The answer is 46.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:49:02 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        811
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      46
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_B_3_1749692934587" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.B.3" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Iris brews a potion using pinches of starflower petal dust. She adds 15 pinches on Monday, 24 on Tuesday. How many pinches in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        34 pinches
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        39 pinches
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        44 pinches
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        78 pinches
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many pinches of starflower petal dust Iris used in total, we need to add the pinches from both days together. On Monday, she used 15 pinches, and on Tuesday, she used 24 pinches. We add these two numbers: 15 + 24. When we add them, we get 39. The answer is 39 pinches.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:48:57 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        770
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      39 pinches
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NBT_3_NBT_A_3_1749692578371" grade="3" domain="NBT" standard="3.NBT.A.3" tier="1">
    <stem>
      42 + 10 = ?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        57
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        104
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        26
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        52
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      42 + 10 = 52
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:42:58 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        0
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      52
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_C_6_1749692556875" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.C.6" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Wren measures 150 grams of powdered unicorn horn for a potion. If she uses 50 grams, how much is left in the cauldron?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        110 grams
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        100 grams
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        200 grams
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        50 grams
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how much powdered unicorn horn is left, we need to subtract the amount Wren used from the total amount she had. Wren started with 150 grams and used 50 grams. So, we calculate 150 grams minus 50 grams. When we subtract 50 from 150, we get 100. The answer is 100 grams.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:42:39 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        796
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      100 grams
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_A_1_1749692547432" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Aurora gains 45 alchemical mastery points every 2 hours. How many points does she earn in 6 hours while brewing a potion?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        135 points
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        140 points
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        270 points
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        137 points
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many points Aurora earns in 6 hours, we first need to know how many 2-hour periods are in 6 hours. Since 6 divided by 2 equals 3, there are 3 periods of 2 hours in 6 hours. Aurora earns 45 points every 2 hours, so we multiply 45 points by 3 periods: 45 x 3 = 135. The answer is 135 points.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:42:31 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        750
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      135 points
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NF_3_NF_A_3_1749692544630" grade="3" domain="NF" standard="3.NF.A.3" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Luna needs 3/4 of a cauldron filled with 100 drops of liquid time. How many drops should she add to the potion?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        75 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        150 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        12 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        7 drops
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many drops Luna needs, we need to calculate 3/4 of 100 drops. First, divide 100 by 4 to find out how much 1/4 is: 100 รท 4 = 25 drops. Next, multiply 25 drops by 3 because we need 3 parts: 25 ร 3 = 75 drops. The answer is 75 drops.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:42:27 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        789
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      75 drops
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_D_8_1749692540969" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.D.8" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Clover brews a potion using 1,200 units of magical energy. She adds another 800 units. How many total units of magical energy are in the potion now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        4,000 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        2,000 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        1,000 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        3,000 units
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many total units of magical energy are in the potion, we need to add the units Clover used. She started with 1,200 units of magical energy and then added another 800 units. We add these two numbers together: 1,200 + 800 = 2,000. The answer is 2,000 units.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:42:24 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        750
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      2,000 units
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_D_8_1749692472615" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.D.8" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Clover brews a potion using 1,200 units of magical energy. She adds 800 more. How many units of magical energy does the potion have now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        1,000 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        4,000 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        3,000 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        2,000 units
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many units of magical energy the potion has now, we start with the 1,200 units Clover used at first. Then, she adds 800 more units. We need to add these two numbers together: 1,200 + 800. When we add them, we get 2,000. The answer is 2,000 units.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:41:16 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        749
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      2,000 units
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_G_3_G_A_1_1749692402052" grade="3" domain="G" standard="3.G.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Ember arranges 12 vials of liquid shadow in equal rows. If each row has 3 vials, how many rows are there in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        6 rows
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        4 rows
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        8 rows
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        5 rows
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many rows Ember can make, we need to divide the total number of vials by the number of vials in each row. Ember has 12 vials and wants to put 3 vials in each row. We divide 12 by 3, which is 12 รท 3 = 4. This means Ember can make 4 rows. The answer is 4 rows.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:40:04 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        746
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      4 rows
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NF_3_NF_A_3_1749692337709" grade="3" domain="NF" standard="3.NF.A.3" tier="1">
    <stem>
      35 + 5 = ?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        35
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        45
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        80
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        40
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      35 + 5 = 40
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:38:57 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        0
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      40
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NF_3_NF_A_1_1749692256704" grade="3" domain="NF" standard="3.NF.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      96 + 14 = ?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        110
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        55
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        220
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        115
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      96 + 14 = 110
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:37:36 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        0
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      110
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_B_4_1749692253885" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.B.4" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Aspen measures 75 drops of liquid time for a potion. Cedar adds 25 more drops. How many drops of liquid time are in the cauldron now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        200 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        50 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        100 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        80 drops
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many drops of liquid time are in the cauldron, we need to add the drops that Aspen and Cedar put in. Aspen starts with 75 drops, and then Cedar adds 25 more drops. We add these two numbers together: 75 + 25 = 100. The answer is 100 drops.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:37:36 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        775
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      100 drops
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NBT_3_NBT_A_1_1749692117818" grade="3" domain="NBT" standard="3.NBT.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      11 + 15 = ?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        26
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        21
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        31
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        52
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      11 + 15 = 26
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:35:18 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        0
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      26
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_A_1_1749692105482" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Cedar needs 4 ounces of moonbeam essence per potion. If he brews 6 potions, how many ounces does he use in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        24 ounces
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        19 ounces
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        48 ounces
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        29 ounces
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many ounces of moonbeam essence Cedar uses, we need to multiply the number of ounces needed for one potion by the number of potions he brews. Cedar needs 4 ounces for each potion, and he is making 6 potions. So, we multiply 4 ounces by 6 potions: 4 x 6 = 24. The answer is 24 ounces.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:35:08 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        749
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      24 ounces
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_G_3_G_A_2_1749692100191" grade="3" domain="G" standard="3.G.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      River has 36 bottles of concentrated lightning. If he arranges them in equal rows of 6 bottles each, how many rows does he create?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        12 rows
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        6 rows
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        8 rows
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        11 rows
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many rows River can make, we need to divide the total number of bottles, which is 36, by the number of bottles in each row, which is 6. We can do this by thinking about how many times 6 fits into 36. When we divide 36 by 6, we get 6 because 6 times 6 equals 36. So, River can make 6 equal rows of bottles. The answer is 6 rows.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:35:03 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        757
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      6 rows
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NBT_3_NBT_A_2_1749692099931" grade="3" domain="NBT" standard="3.NBT.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      44 + 25 = ?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        138
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        74
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        64
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        69
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      44 + 25 = 69
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:35:00 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        0
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      69
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_C_7_1749691981579" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.C.7" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Briar needs 300 milliliters of concentrated lightning. She already has 120 milliliters. How much more does she need to brew her potion?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        90 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        180 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        300 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        360 milliliters
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how much more concentrated lightning Briar needs, we start with the total amount she needs, which is 300 milliliters. She already has 120 milliliters. We subtract the amount she has from the total amount needed: 300 milliliters - 120 milliliters = 180 milliliters. The answer is 180 milliliters.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:33:04 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        808
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      180 milliliters
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_C_7_1749691856635" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.C.7" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Briar brews a potion with 300 milliliters of concentrated lightning. If Rowan adds 150 milliliters more, how many milliliters are in the potion now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        450 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        900 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        225 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        300 milliliters
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how much potion Briar and Rowan have together, we need to add the amounts they each put in. Briar starts with 300 milliliters of concentrated lightning. Then, Rowan adds 150 milliliters more. We add these two amounts together: 300 milliliters + 150 milliliters = 450 milliliters. The answer is 450 milliliters.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:30:59 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        823
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      450 milliliters
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_C_5_1749691850627" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.C.5" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Vale has a cauldron holding 20 ounces of moonbeam essence. If he adds 15 more ounces, how much moonbeam essence is in the cauldron now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        40 ounces
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        70 ounces
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        30 ounces
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        35 ounces
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how much moonbeam essence is in the cauldron now, we need to add the amount Vale already has to the amount he is adding. Vale starts with 20 ounces of moonbeam essence and then adds 15 more ounces. We add these two numbers together: 20 + 15 = 35. The answer is 35 ounces.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:30:53 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        750
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      35 ounces
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_G_3_G_A_1_1749691639167" grade="3" domain="G" standard="3.G.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Ember arranges 12 vials of liquid shadow in equal rows. If each row has 3 vials, how many rows does she have?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        8 rows
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        6 rows
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        4 rows
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        2 rows
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many rows Ember has, we need to divide the total number of vials by the number of vials in each row. Ember has 12 vials, and each row has 3 vials. So, we divide 12 by 3: \[ 12 \div 3 = 4 \] This means Ember has 4 rows. The answer is 4 rows.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:27:21 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        743
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      4 rows
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_B_3_1749691554039" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.B.3" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Iris brews a potion using 150 pinches of starflower petal dust. If she uses 50 pinches per potion, how many potions can she make?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        5 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        1 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        3 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        6 potions
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many potions Iris can make, we need to divide the total pinches of starflower petal dust by the number of pinches she uses for each potion. Iris has 150 pinches of starflower petal dust, and she uses 50 pinches for each potion. We divide 150 by 50, which is 150 รท 50 = 3. The answer is 3 potions.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:25:59 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        776
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      3 potions
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_A_2_1749691551045" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Felix needs 45 drops of crystallized dragon tears for a potion. He has 28 drops. How many more drops does he need?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        19 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        22 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        34 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        17 drops
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many more drops Felix needs, we start with the total number of drops he needs, which is 45. Then, we subtract the number of drops he already has, which is 28. So, we calculate 45 minus 28. First, we can subtract 28 from 45 like this: 45 - 28 ____ 17 Felix needs 17 more drops to have a total of 45 drops. The answer is 17 drops.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:25:54 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        764
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      17 drops
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NF_3_NF_A_1_1749691410571" grade="3" domain="NF" standard="3.NF.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Elara uses 3 arcane flame sources to brew a potion. She uses 1 source for each potion. What fraction of the sources is used for 1 potion?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        3/3
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        6/3
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        1/3
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        2/3
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out what fraction of the arcane flame sources Elara uses for one potion, we start by knowing she has 3 sources in total. Since she uses 1 source for each potion, we need to divide the 1 source by the total number of sources, which is 3. This means we are finding the fraction 1 out of 3, which is written as 1/3. The answer is 1/3.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:23:33 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        772
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      1/3
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_C_6_1749691394665" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.C.6" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Wren measures 150 grams of powdered unicorn horn for a potion. Later, she adds 50 grams more. How many grams of unicorn horn does she have now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        400 grams
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        100 grams
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        200 grams
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        150 grams
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many grams of unicorn horn Wren has now, we start with the amount she measured first, which is 150 grams. Then, she adds 50 grams more to the 150 grams. We add these two amounts together: 150 grams + 50 grams = 200 grams. The answer is 200 grams.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:23:17 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        796
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      200 grams
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_A_1_1749691379087" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Cedar needs 4 ounces of moonbeam essence for each potion. If he brews 7 potions, how many ounces does he use in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        56 ounces
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        28 ounces
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        33 ounces
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        23 ounces
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many ounces of moonbeam essence Cedar uses in total, we need to multiply the number of ounces needed for one potion by the number of potions he brews. Cedar needs 4 ounces for each potion, and he brews 7 potions. So, we calculate \(4 \times 7 = 28\). The answer is 28 ounces.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:23:01 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        747
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      28 ounces
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NBT_3_NBT_A_3_1749691371814" grade="3" domain="NBT" standard="3.NBT.A.3" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Ocean uses 47 crystal essence extractors to brew potions. If each extractor can be used 10 times, how many total uses are possible?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        470 uses
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        47 uses
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        940 uses
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        235 uses
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many total uses are possible, we need to multiply the number of extractors by the number of times each can be used. Ocean has 47 extractors, and each one can be used 10 times. So, we multiply 47 by 10, which equals 470. The answer is 470 uses.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:22:54 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        733
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      470 uses
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_A_2_1749691355832" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Felix needs 50 drops of crystallized dragon tears for a potion. He has 32 drops. How many more drops does he need to collect?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        36 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        18 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        20 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        23 drops
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many more drops Felix needs, we start with the total number of drops he needs, which is 50. Then, we subtract the number of drops he already has, which is 32. So, we do the subtraction: 50 - 32 = 18. The answer is 18 drops.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:22:38 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        733
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      18 drops
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NF_3_NF_A_1_1749691346609" grade="3" domain="NF" standard="3.NF.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Elara uses 3 arcane flame sources to brew a potion. If each source represents 1/4 of the total needed, how many sources are required?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        12 sources
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        14 sources
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        17 sources
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        24 sources
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many arcane flame sources Elara needs, we start by knowing that each source is 1/4 of the total needed. This means 4 sources make up 1 whole potion. Since Elara uses 3 whole potions, we multiply 4 sources by 3 potions: 4 x 3 = 12. The answer is 12 sources.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:22:29 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        753
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      12 sources
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NF_3_NF_A_3_1749691269903" grade="3" domain="NF" standard="3.NF.A.3" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Luna has 3/4 of a vial of drops of liquid time. She uses 1/4. What fraction of the vial is left for her potion?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        2/2
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        1/2
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        3/2
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        7/2
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      Luna starts with 3/4 of a vial of drops of liquid time. She uses 1/4 of the vial, so we need to subtract 1/4 from 3/4. To do this, we subtract the numerators: 3 - 1 = 2, and keep the same denominator, which is 4. This gives us 2/4 of the vial left. We can simplify 2/4 by dividing both the numerator and the denominator by 2, which gives us 1/2. The answer is 1/2.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:21:13 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        832
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      1/2
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_D_8_1749691129880" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.D.8" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Clover brews a potion with 300 units of magical energy. She adds 150 more units. How many total units of magical energy does the potion have now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        450 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        300 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        900 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        225 units
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many total units of magical energy the potion has, we need to add the two amounts together. Clover starts with 300 units of magical energy and then adds 150 more units. We add these numbers: 300 + 150 = 450. The answer is 450 units.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:18:52 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        729
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      450 units
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NF_3_NF_A_2_1749691126308" grade="3" domain="NF" standard="3.NF.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Finn uses 3 enchanted mortar and pestles to grind 1/4 of a magical herb. How much herb does each mortar and pestle grind?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        1/12
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        2/22
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        3/32
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        6/62
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how much herb each mortar and pestle grinds, we need to divide the 1/4 of the herb equally among the 3 mortar and pestles. We do this by dividing the fraction 1/4 by 3. In math, dividing by a whole number is the same as multiplying by the fraction of that number, so we multiply 1/4 by 1/3. This gives us 1/4 ร 1/3 = 1/12. The answer is 1/12.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:18:49 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        782
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      1/12
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_C_7_1749691116709" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.C.7" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Briar mixed 200 milliliters of concentrated lightning with 300 milliliters more. How many milliliters are in the cauldron now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        1000 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        250 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        500 milliliters
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        200 milliliters
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many milliliters are in the cauldron, we need to add the amounts of concentrated lightning together. Briar first mixed 200 milliliters, and then added 300 milliliters more. We add these two amounts: 200 milliliters + 300 milliliters = 500 milliliters. The answer is 500 milliliters.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:18:39 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        811
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      500 milliliters
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_B_4_1749691043735" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.B.4" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Aspen brews a potion using 15 drops of liquid time. Cedar uses 25 drops. How many more drops does Cedar use than Aspen?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        10 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        12 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        15 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        20 drops
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many more drops Cedar uses than Aspen, we need to subtract the number of drops Aspen uses from the number of drops Cedar uses. Cedar uses 25 drops, and Aspen uses 15 drops. So, we calculate 25 - 15, which equals 10. The answer is 10 drops.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:17:25 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        764
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      10 drops
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NBT_3_NBT_A_3_1749691039344" grade="3" domain="NBT" standard="3.NBT.A.3" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Ocean needs 47 crystal essence extractors for a potion. If each box contains 10 extractors, how many boxes should Ocean order?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        7 boxes
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        3 boxes
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        5 boxes
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        10 boxes
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many boxes Ocean needs, we first divide the total number of extractors by the number of extractors in each box. Since Ocean needs 47 extractors and each box contains 10 extractors, we divide 47 by 10. This gives us 4 full boxes with 7 extractors left over. Since we can't order a part of a box, Ocean needs to order one more box to have enough extractors. The answer is 5 boxes.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:17:23 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        758
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      5 boxes
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_C_5_1749690752243" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.C.5" tier="1">
    <stem>
      In Vale's cauldron, 15 ounces of moonbeam essence are added. If the cauldron holds 50 ounces, what fraction of the cauldron is filled?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        17/50 or 3/10
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        15/50 or 3/10
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        20/50 or 3/10
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        30/50 or 3/10
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out what fraction of the cauldron is filled, we need to compare the amount of moonbeam essence added to the total capacity of the cauldron. Vale added 15 ounces of moonbeam essence, and the cauldron can hold 50 ounces in total. We write this as a fraction: 15/50. To simplify the fraction, we divide both the top number (numerator) and the bottom number (denominator) by their greatest common factor, which is 5. So, 15 divided by 5 is 3, and 50 divided by 5 is 10. Therefore, the simplified fraction is 3/10. The answer is 15/50 or 3/10.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:12:35 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        846
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      15/50 or 3/10
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NBT_3_NBT_A_1_1749690570141" grade="3" domain="NBT" standard="3.NBT.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Meadow brews 24 invisibility draught flasks. She needs 45. How many more flasks must Meadow brew to reach her goal?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        21 flasks
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        42 flasks
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        26 flasks
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        29 flasks
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many more flasks Meadow needs to brew, we start with her goal of 45 flasks. She has already brewed 24 flasks. We need to subtract the number of flasks she has from her goal: 45 - 24. When we do the subtraction, we find that 45 - 24 equals 21. The answer is 21 flasks.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:09:33 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        757
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      21 flasks
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NBT_3_NBT_A_2_1749690559646" grade="3" domain="NBT" standard="3.NBT.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Storm brewed 46 levitation tonic containers. He gave Jasper 23 containers. How many containers does Storm have left?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        28 containers
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        33 containers
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        46 containers
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        23 containers
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many containers Storm has left, we need to subtract the number of containers he gave to Jasper from the total number he brewed. Start with the total number of containers, which is 46, and subtract the 23 containers he gave away: 46 - 23 = 23. The answer is 23 containers.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:09:21 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        721
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      23 containers
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_G_3_G_A_2_1749690556152" grade="3" domain="G" standard="3.G.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      River arranges 36 bottles of concentrated lightning into equal rows for a potion. Which could be the number of bottles in each row?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        11 bottles
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        6 bottles
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        8 bottles
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        12 bottles
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many bottles River can put in each row, we need to divide the total number of bottles, which is 36, by a number that divides evenly into 36. We can try dividing 36 by different numbers to see which one works. If we divide 36 by 6, we get 6, because 36 divided by 6 equals 6 with no leftovers. This means River can arrange the bottles into 6 rows of 6 bottles each. The answer is 6 bottles.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:09:19 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        756
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      6 bottles
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_A_1_1749690544053" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Aurora earned 150 alchemical mastery points in 2 hours. How many points does she earn per hour while brewing potions?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        150 points per hour
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        152 points per hour
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        80 points per hour
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        75 points per hour
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many points Aurora earns per hour, we need to divide the total points by the number of hours. She earned 150 points in 2 hours, so we divide 150 by 2. When we do the division, 150 divided by 2 equals 75. The answer is 75 points per hour.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:09:06 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        728
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      75 points per hour
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NF_3_NF_A_1_1749690183138" grade="3" domain="NF" standard="3.NF.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Elara uses 3 out of 5 magical herbs to brew a potion. What fraction of the herbs did she use?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        3/5
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        5/5
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        1/5
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        6/5
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out what fraction of the herbs Elara used, we need to compare the number of herbs she used to the total number of herbs. Elara used 3 herbs, and there are 5 herbs in total. We write this as a fraction: the number of herbs used (3) over the total number of herbs (5), which is written as 3/5. The answer is 3/5.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:03:07 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        740
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      3/5
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_C_5_1749690181309" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.C.5" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Vale brews a potion earning 120 alchemical points. If each potion earns 40 points, how many potions did Vale brew?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        3 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        6 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        1 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        5 potions
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many potions Vale brewed, we need to divide the total alchemical points by the points each potion earns. Vale earned 120 points, and each potion earns 40 points. So, we divide 120 by 40: \[ 120 \div 40 = 3 \] This means Vale brewed 3 potions. The answer is 3 potions.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:03:03 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        738
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      3 potions
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_D_8_1749690158293" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.D.8" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Clover has 150 ml of starlight essence. She uses 60 ml in a potion. How much starlight essence is left?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        180 ml
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        90 ml
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        100 ml
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        45 ml
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how much starlight essence Clover has left, we need to subtract the amount she used from the total amount she started with. Clover started with 150 ml of starlight essence and used 60 ml in a potion. We do the subtraction: 150 ml - 60 ml = 90 ml. The answer is 90 ml.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:02:42 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        733
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      90 ml
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_A_2_1749690132192" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Felix needs 150 ml of starlight essence for a potion. He has 90 ml. How much more does he need?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        60 ml
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        120 ml
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        150 ml
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        30 ml
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how much more starlight essence Felix needs, we start with the total amount he needs, which is 150 ml. He already has 90 ml. We need to subtract the amount he has from the total amount he needs: 150 ml - 90 ml = 60 ml. So, Felix needs 60 ml more of starlight essence. The answer is 60 ml.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:02:14 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        738
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      60 ml
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NF_3_NF_A_2_1749690066728" grade="3" domain="NF" standard="3.NF.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Finn has 8 crystal vials. He fills 3/8 of them with a magical potion. How many vials are filled?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        6 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        3 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        5 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        1 vials
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many vials Finn fills, we need to calculate 3/8 of 8 vials. First, we divide the 8 vials into 8 equal parts, which means each part is 1 vial. Then, we take 3 of those parts because Finn fills 3/8 of the vials. So, 3 parts of 1 vial each is 3 vials. The answer is 3 vials.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:01:10 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        752
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      3 vials
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_A_1_1749690058426" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Aurora starts brewing at 2:15 PM. She adds unicorn tears for 45 minutes. What time does she finish adding the tears?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        5:00 PM
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        4:00 PM
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        6:00 PM
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        3:00 PM
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out what time Aurora finishes adding unicorn tears, we start at 2:15 PM. She adds the tears for 45 minutes. First, we add 15 minutes to 2:15 PM, which brings us to 2:30 PM. Then, we add the remaining 30 minutes to 2:30 PM, which brings us to 3:00 PM. The answer is 3:00 PM.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Thu Jun 12 2025 01:01:04 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        747
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      3:00 PM
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_A_1_1749666227591" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Finn has 5 crystal vials. Each vial holds 3 magical ingredients. How many magical ingredients does Finn have in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        15 ingredients
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        20 ingredients
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        17 ingredients
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        30 ingredients
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many magical ingredients Finn has in total, we need to multiply the number of vials by the number of ingredients each vial holds. Finn has 5 vials, and each vial holds 3 ingredients. So, we multiply 5 by 3, which equals 15. The answer is 15 ingredients.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 18:23:50 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        0
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      15 ingredients
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_A_1_1749666204714" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Finn has 5 crystal vials. He brews 3 potions in each vial. How many potions does Finn have in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        15 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        20 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        30 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        17 potions
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many potions Finn has in total, we need to multiply the number of vials by the number of potions in each vial. Finn has 5 vials, and each vial contains 3 potions. So, we multiply 5 by 3, which equals 15. The answer is 15 potions.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 18:23:27 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        0
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      15 potions
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_A_1_1749666176464" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Finn has 4 crystal vials. Each vial holds 3 magical ingredients. How many ingredients does Finn have in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        12 ingredients
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        14 ingredients
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        17 ingredients
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        24 ingredients
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many magical ingredients Finn has in total, we need to multiply the number of vials by the number of ingredients each vial holds. Finn has 4 vials, and each vial holds 3 ingredients. So, we multiply 4 by 3, which equals 12. The answer is 12 ingredients.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 18:22:59 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        0
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      12 ingredients
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_A_1_1749666110485" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Finn has 5 crystal vials. Each vial holds 3 magical ingredients. How many magical ingredients does Finn have in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        15
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        20
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        17
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        30
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many magical ingredients Finn has in total, we need to multiply the number of vials by the number of ingredients each vial holds. Finn has 5 vials, and each vial holds 3 magical ingredients. So, we calculate 5 times 3, which equals 15. The answer is 15.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 18:21:55 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        0
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      15
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_A_1_1749665982136" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Finn has 4 crystal vials. Each vial holds 3 magical herbs. How many herbs does Finn have in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        24 herbs
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        14 herbs
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        17 herbs
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        12 herbs
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many magical herbs Finn has in total, we need to multiply the number of vials by the number of herbs each vial holds. Finn has 4 vials, and each vial holds 3 herbs. So, we calculate 4 times 3, which equals 12. The answer is 12 herbs.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 18:19:44 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        0
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      12 herbs
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_A_1_1749665962216" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Jordan finds 17 books and then finds 2 more books. How many books in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        38
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        24
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        19
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        34
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To solve this problem, we need to addition the numbers. The answer is 19.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 18:19:23 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        0
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      19
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_A_1_1749665933877" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Jordan finds 17 books and then finds 2 more books. How many books in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        38
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        34
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        24
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        19
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To solve this problem, we need to addition the numbers. The answer is 19.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 18:18:55 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        0
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      19
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_A_1_1749665908659" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Jordan finds 17 books and then finds 2 more books. How many books in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        38
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        19
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        24
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        34
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To solve this problem, we need to addition the numbers. The answer is 19.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 18:18:32 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        0
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      19
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_C_6_1749665703223" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.C.6" tier="3">
    <stem>
      A box has 44 stickers. 19 stickers are taken out. How many stickers are left?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        35
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        30
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        25
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        50
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To solve this problem, we need to subtraction the numbers. The answer is 25.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 18:15:03 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        0
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      25
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_A_3_1749665703018" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.A.3" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Quinn counts 13 cookies in one group and 8 cookies in another group. How many cookies altogether?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        16
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        42
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        21
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        26
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To solve this problem, we need to counting the numbers. The answer is 21.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 18:15:03 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        0
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      21
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_B_5_1749665702608" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.B.5" tier="1">
    <stem>
      A box has 34 crayons. 11 crayons are taken out. How many crayons are left?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        46
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        23
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        45
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        33
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To solve this problem, we need to subtraction the numbers. The answer is 23.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 18:15:02 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        0
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      23
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_A_1_1749611551680" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Ruby has 5 vials of starlight essence. If she finds 3 more, how many vials does she have in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        15 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        8 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        13 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        16 vials
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many vials of starlight essence Ruby has in total, we start with the number of vials she already has, which is 5. Then, we add the 3 more vials she finds. We can write this as a math problem: 5 + 3. When we add these numbers together, we get 8. So, Ruby has 8 vials of starlight essence in total. The answer is 8 vials.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 03:12:34 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        859
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      8 vials
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_B_6_1749611533389" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.B.6" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Luna has 10 phoenix feathers and collects 8 more. How many phoenix feathers does she have now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        36 feathers
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        18 feathers
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        20 feathers
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        23 feathers
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many phoenix feathers Luna has now, we start with the number of feathers she already has, which is 10. Then, we add the 8 more feathers she collects. We can write this as a math problem: 10 + 8. When we add these numbers together, we get 18. So, Luna has 18 feathers now. The answer is 18 feathers.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 03:12:15 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        820
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      18 feathers
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NBT_3_NBT_A_3_1749611530496" grade="3" domain="NBT" standard="3.NBT.A.3" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Storm uses magic flames to heat 125 ml of potion. If he adds 75 ml more, how much potion does he have now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        100 ml
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        200 ml
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        130 ml
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        400 ml
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how much potion Storm has after adding more, we start with the amount he already has, which is 125 ml. Then, we add the 75 ml of potion he adds. We can write this as a math problem: 125 ml + 75 ml = 200 ml. So, after adding the two amounts together, Storm now has a total of 200 ml of potion. The answer is 200 ml.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 03:12:13 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        841
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      200 ml
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_D_8_1749611417588" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.D.8" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Felix has 5 vials of phoenix feathers and 3 vials of dragon tears. How many vials of spell ingredients does he have in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        16 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        13 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        15 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        8 vials
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many vials of spell ingredients Felix has, we need to add the number of vials of phoenix feathers to the number of vials of dragon tears. Felix has 5 vials of phoenix feathers and 3 vials of dragon tears. We can write this as a math problem: 5 + 3. When we add 5 and 3 together, we get 8. So, Felix has a total of 8 vials of spell ingredients. The answer is 8 vials.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 03:10:21 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        864
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      8 vials
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NF_3_NF_A_2_1749611386122" grade="3" domain="NF" standard="3.NF.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Willow has 3 vials of fairy dust. Each vial contains 2 ounces. How many ounces of fairy dust does Willow have in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        6 ounces
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        11 ounces
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        12 ounces
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        8 ounces
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how much fairy dust Willow has in total, we need to multiply the number of vials by the amount of fairy dust in each vial. Willow has 3 vials, and each vial contains 2 ounces of fairy dust. So, we can do the multiplication: 3 vials ร 2 ounces per vial = 6 ounces. This means that Willow has a total of 6 ounces of fairy dust. The answer is 6 ounces.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 03:09:49 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        849
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      6 ounces
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_B_3_1749611310099" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.B.3" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Clover has 5 vials of phoenix feathers and 3 vials of dragon tears. How many vials of spell ingredients does she have in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        13 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        16 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        8 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        15 vials
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many vials of spell ingredients Clover has, we need to add the number of vials of phoenix feathers to the number of vials of dragon tears. Clover has 5 vials of phoenix feathers and 3 vials of dragon tears. Now, we can add these two numbers together: 5 vials + 3 vials = 8 vials. So, Clover has a total of 8 vials of spell ingredients. The answer is 8 vials.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 03:08:32 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        859
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      8 vials
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_D_8_1749611298279" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.D.8" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Hazel has 248 cauldron bubbles. If she brews 56 more, how many bubbles will she have in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        304 bubbles
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        254 bubbles
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        608 bubbles
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        192 bubbles
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many cauldron bubbles Hazel will have in total, we need to add the number of bubbles she already has to the number of bubbles she brews. Hazel starts with 248 bubbles and brews 56 more. First, we write the addition problem: 248 + 56. Now, let's add the two numbers together. When we add 248 and 56, we get 304. So, Hazel will have a total of 304 bubbles after brewing more. The answer is 304 bubbles.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 03:08:22 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        860
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      304 bubbles
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NF_3_NF_A_2_1749611248337" grade="3" domain="NF" standard="3.NF.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Cedar has 3 vials of unicorn tears. Each vial contains 1/4 cup. How much unicorn tears does Cedar have in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        6/4 cup
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        4/4 cup
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        3/4 cup
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        5/4 cup
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how much unicorn tears Cedar has in total, we need to add the amount in each vial together. Each vial has 1/4 cup of unicorn tears, and there are 3 vials. We can write this as: 1/4 + 1/4 + 1/4. Now, let's add them up. When we add 1/4 three times, we get: 1/4 + 1/4 = 2/4, and then adding another 1/4 gives us: 2/4 + 1/4 = 3/4. So, Cedar has a total of 3/4 cup of unicorn tears. The answer is 3/4 cup.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 03:07:32 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        915
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      3/4 cup
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NF_3_NF_A_1_1749611217631" grade="3" domain="NF" standard="3.NF.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Luna has 2 phoenix feathers. If she buys 3 more, how many phoenix feathers does she have in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        6 phoenix feathers
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        7 phoenix feathers
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        5 phoenix feathers
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        10 phoenix feathers
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many phoenix feathers Luna has in total, we start with the number of feathers she already has, which is 2. Then, we add the 3 feathers she buys to that number. So, we can write it as: 2 (the feathers she has) + 3 (the feathers she buys) = 5. Now we see that when we add 2 and 3 together, we get 5. The answer is 5 phoenix feathers.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 03:07:00 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        847
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      5 phoenix feathers
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_A_2_1749611186751" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Felix adds 5 drops of liquid time to his cauldron. If he adds 3 more, how many drops are in the cauldron now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        15 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        8 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        16 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        13 drops
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many drops of liquid Felix has in his cauldron, we start with the 5 drops he already added. Then, he adds 3 more drops. We can find the total number of drops by adding these two numbers together: 5 drops + 3 drops = 8 drops. So, after adding the drops, there are 8 drops in the cauldron now. The answer is 8 drops.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 03:06:29 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        851
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      8 drops
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_A_2_1749611001094" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Iris collected 5 vials of unicorn tears. If each vial holds 3 drops, how many drops of unicorn tears does she have in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        30 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        20 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        17 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        15 drops
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many drops of unicorn tears Iris has in total, we need to multiply the number of vials by the number of drops in each vial. Iris has 5 vials, and each vial holds 3 drops. We can write this as a multiplication problem: 5 vials ร 3 drops per vial = 15 drops. So, Iris has a total of 15 drops of unicorn tears. The answer is 15 drops.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 03:03:24 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        847
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      15 drops
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_A_1_1749610993142" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Ruby uses magic flames to heat 3 cauldrons. Each cauldron needs 5 minutes. How many minutes does Ruby need in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        20 minutes
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        30 minutes
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        17 minutes
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        15 minutes
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many minutes Ruby needs to heat all three cauldrons, we can use multiplication. Each cauldron takes 5 minutes, and there are 3 cauldrons. So, we multiply 5 minutes by 3 cauldrons: 5 minutes ร 3 = 15 minutes. This means Ruby needs a total of 15 minutes to heat all the cauldrons. The answer is 15 minutes.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 03:03:15 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        847
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      15 minutes
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_C_6_1749610958282" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.C.6" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Willow has 5 vials of mystic powders. If she uses 2 vials, how many vials remain?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        4 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        5 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        6 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        3 vials
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many vials of mystic powders Willow has left, we start with the total number of vials she has, which is 5. Then, we need to subtract the number of vials she used, which is 2. We can write this as a math problem: 5 vials - 2 vials = 3 vials. So, after using 2 vials, Willow has 3 vials remaining. The answer is 3 vials.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 03:02:42 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        850
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      3 vials
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_B_3_1749610915249" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.B.3" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Vale collected 12 vials of fairy dust. If Sage gives him 8 more, how many vials does Vale have now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        20 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        40 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        22 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        25 vials
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many vials of fairy dust Vale has now, we start with the number of vials he already has, which is 12. Then, we add the 8 vials that Sage gives him. So, we can write the math like this: 12 vials + 8 vials = 20 vials. After adding, we see that Vale now has a total of 20 vials of fairy dust. The answer is 20 vials.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 03:01:57 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        849
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      20 vials
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_C_7_1749610814531" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.C.7" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Jasper collected 15 drops of unicorn tears. If he uses 5 drops for each potion, how many potions can he make?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        3 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        6 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        1 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        5 potions
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many potions Jasper can make, we need to divide the total number of drops he has by the number of drops needed for each potion. Jasper has 15 drops of unicorn tears and he uses 5 drops for each potion. We can do the math like this: 15 drops รท 5 drops per potion = 3 potions. So, Jasper can make 3 potions with the drops he collected. The answer is 3 potions.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 03:00:17 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        850
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      3 potions
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NBT_3_NBT_A_2_1749610793730" grade="3" domain="NBT" standard="3.NBT.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Clover adds 212 bubbles to her cauldron. If 100 bubbles pop, how many bubbles remain?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        112 bubbles
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        212 bubbles
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        224 bubbles
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        56 bubbles
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      Clover starts with 212 bubbles in her cauldron. If 100 bubbles pop, we need to find out how many bubbles are left. First, we subtract the 100 popped bubbles from the 212 bubbles: 212 - 100 = 112. So, after the bubbles pop, Clover has 112 bubbles remaining. The answer is 112 bubbles.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 02:59:55 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        819
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      112 bubbles
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NF_3_NF_A_1_1749610762694" grade="3" domain="NF" standard="3.NF.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Elara has 2/3 of a vial of phoenix feathers and 1/3 of a vial of dragon tears. How much potion does she have in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        1 vial
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        3 vial
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        6 vial
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        2 vial
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how much potion Elara has in total, we need to add the fractions of the two ingredients together. She has 2/3 of a vial of phoenix feathers and 1/3 of a vial of dragon tears. To add these fractions, we keep the same bottom number (denominator), which is 3, and we add the top numbers (numerators) together: 2 + 1 = 3. So, we have 3/3 of a vial. Since 3/3 is the same as 1 whole vial, Elara has a total of 1 vial of potion. The answer is 1 vial.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 02:59:26 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        901
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      1 vial
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_A_4_1749610757814" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.A.4" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Clover has 5 phoenix feathers. If Ivy gives her 3 more, how many phoenix feathers does Clover have in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        13 phoenix feathers
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        15 phoenix feathers
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        16 phoenix feathers
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        8 phoenix feathers
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many phoenix feathers Clover has in total, we start with the number of feathers she already has, which is 5. Then, we add the 3 feathers that Ivy gives her. So, we do the math like this: 5 (Clover's feathers) + 3 (feathers from Ivy) = 8 feathers. Now we know that Clover has 8 phoenix feathers in total. The answer is 8 phoenix feathers.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 02:59:20 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        842
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      8 phoenix feathers
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_B_6_1749610667895" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.B.6" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Finn has 8 elixir bottles. He brews 5 more. How many elixir bottles does Finn have now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        13 bottles
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        18 bottles
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        26 bottles
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        15 bottles
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many elixir bottles Finn has now, we start with the number of bottles he already has, which is 8. Then, we add the 5 more bottles he brews. We can write this as a math problem: 8 (the bottles he has) + 5 (the bottles he brews) = 13. So, when we add 8 and 5 together, we get 13. The answer is 13 bottles.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 02:57:51 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        841
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      13 bottles
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_D_8_1749610620683" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.D.8" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Aurora has 8 elixir bottles. She adds 5 more. How many elixir bottles does she have now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        13 elixir bottles
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        26 elixir bottles
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        15 elixir bottles
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        18 elixir bottles
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many elixir bottles Aurora has now, we start with the number of bottles she already has, which is 8. Then, we add the 5 more bottles she gets. We can write this as a math equation: 8 + 5 = 13. So, when we add 8 and 5 together, we find that Aurora has 13 elixir bottles now. The answer is 13 elixir bottles.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 02:57:03 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        840
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      13 elixir bottles
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_C_5_1749610554967" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.C.5" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Luna's cauldron bubbles rise 194 times while brewing. If each bubble lasts 2 seconds, how long do they last in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        388 seconds
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        194 seconds
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        196 seconds
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        776 seconds
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how long Luna's bubbles last in total, we need to multiply the number of bubbles by how long each bubble lasts. Luna's cauldron bubbles rise 194 times, and each bubble lasts 2 seconds. So, we do the math like this: 194 bubbles ร 2 seconds per bubble = 388 seconds. This means all the bubbles together last for 388 seconds. The answer is 388 seconds.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 02:55:58 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        844
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      388 seconds
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_A_3_1749610499037" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.A.3" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Vale has 5 vials of mystic powders. If he finds 8 more, how many vials does he have now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        26 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        18 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        13 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        15 vials
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many vials of mystic powders Vale has now, we need to add the number of vials he already has to the number of vials he finds. Vale starts with 5 vials and then finds 8 more vials. We can write this as a math problem: 5 + 8. When we add these two numbers together, we get 13. So, Vale has 13 vials of mystic powders now. The answer is 13 vials.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 02:55:01 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        857
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      13 vials
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_G_3_G_A_2_1749610481456" grade="3" domain="G" standard="3.G.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Hazel sees 5 cauldrons bubbling. Each cauldron has 3 bubbles. How many bubbles are there in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        15 bubbles
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        20 bubbles
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        30 bubbles
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        17 bubbles
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many bubbles there are in total, we need to multiply the number of cauldrons by the number of bubbles in each cauldron. Hazel sees 5 cauldrons, and each cauldron has 3 bubbles. So, we can do the math like this: 5 cauldrons ร 3 bubbles = 15 bubbles. This means there are 15 bubbles in total. The answer is 15 bubbles.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 02:54:43 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        841
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      15 bubbles
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_C_7_1749610449828" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.C.7" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Sage collected 2 vials of starlight essence. If Iris gives him 4 more, how many vials of starlight essence does Sage have now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        6 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        12 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        11 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        8 vials
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      Sage starts with 2 vials of starlight essence. Then, Iris gives him 4 more vials. To find out how many vials Sage has now, we need to add the vials he already has to the vials Iris gave him. So, we do the math: 2 vials + 4 vials = 6 vials. The answer is 6 vials.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 02:54:12 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        855
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      6 vials
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_A_4_1749610441020" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.A.4" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Briar has 235 crystal vials. If she gives away 48 vials, how many vials does she have left?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        283 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        187 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        197 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        374 vials
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many crystal vials Briar has left after giving away some, we need to subtract the number of vials she gives away from the total number she originally has. Briar starts with 235 vials and gives away 48 vials. We can write this as a subtraction problem: 235 - 48. Now, let's do the subtraction step by step. First, we can subtract 40 from 235, which gives us 195. Then, we subtract the remaining 8 vials from 195. So, 195 - 8 equals 187. After giving away 48 vials, Briar has 187 vials left. The answer is 187 vials.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 02:54:04 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        904
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      187 vials
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_OA_3_OA_B_5_1749610419497" grade="3" domain="OA" standard="3.OA.B.5" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Meadow has 5 vials of unicorn tears. If she gives 2 to Hazel, how many vials does Meadow have left?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        5 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        6 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        3 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        4 vials
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many vials of unicorn tears Meadow has left, we start with the number of vials she originally has, which is 5. Then, we need to subtract the 2 vials she gives to Hazel. So, we calculate: 5 vials - 2 vials = 3 vials. This means Meadow has 3 vials of unicorn tears left after giving some to Hazel. The answer is 3 vials.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 02:53:42 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        848
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      3 vials
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_A_2_1749610405828" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Aurora has 5 crystal vials. She brews 3 potions in each vial. How many potions does she brew in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        20 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        30 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        15 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        17 potions
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many potions Aurora brews in total, we need to multiply the number of vials by the number of potions in each vial. Aurora has 5 crystal vials, and she brews 3 potions in each vial. So, we can do the math like this: 5 vials ร 3 potions per vial = 15 potions. Therefore, the total number of potions she brews is 15. The answer is 15 potions.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 02:53:29 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        860
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      15 potions
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_G_3_G_A_1_1749610393673" grade="3" domain="G" standard="3.G.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Luna has 5 vials of phoenix feathers and 3 vials of dragon tears. How many vials of spell ingredients does she have in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        16 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        8 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        13 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        15 vials
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many vials of spell ingredients Luna has in total, we need to add the number of vials of phoenix feathers to the number of vials of dragon tears. Luna has 5 vials of phoenix feathers and 3 vials of dragon tears. Now, we can add these two numbers together: 5 (phoenix feathers) + 3 (dragon tears) = 8 (total vials). So, Luna has 8 vials of spell ingredients in total. The answer is 8 vials.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 02:53:16 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        863
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      8 vials
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NBT_3_NBT_A_1_1749610387058" grade="3" domain="NBT" standard="3.NBT.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Aspen collected 208 vials of starlight essence. If she uses 100 vials, how many vials remain?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        54 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        308 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        216 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        108 vials
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many vials of starlight essence Aspen has left after using some, we start with the total number of vials she collected, which is 208. Then, we need to subtract the number of vials she used, which is 100. We can write this as a math problem: 208 - 100 = ? Now, we can do the subtraction. When we take 100 away from 208, we get 108. So, Aspen has 108 vials remaining. The answer is 108 vials.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 02:53:11 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        871
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      108 vials
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_D_8_1749609271309" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.D.8" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Clover has 5 vials of phoenix feathers and 3 vials of dragon tears. How many vials of spell ingredients does she have in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        16 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        8 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        13 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        15 vials
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many vials of spell ingredients Clover has, we need to add the number of vials of phoenix feathers and dragon tears together. Clover has 5 vials of phoenix feathers and 3 vials of dragon tears. Now, we can add these two numbers: 5 (phoenix feathers) + 3 (dragon tears) = 8. So, Clover has a total of 8 vials of spell ingredients. The answer is 8 vials.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 02:34:35 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        856
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      8 vials
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_C_5_1749609242520" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.C.5" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Vale collected 15 vials of fairy dust. If each vial holds 2 ounces, how many ounces of fairy dust does Vale have in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        30 ounces
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        35 ounces
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        60 ounces
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        25 ounces
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many ounces of fairy dust Vale has, we need to multiply the number of vials by the amount of fairy dust each vial holds. Vale has 15 vials, and each vial holds 2 ounces. So, we can do the math like this: 15 vials ร 2 ounces per vial = 30 ounces. This means Vale has a total of 30 ounces of fairy dust. The answer is 30 ounces.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 02:34:06 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        846
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      30 ounces
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NBT_3_NBT_A_2_1749609183723" grade="3" domain="NBT" standard="3.NBT.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Storm has 125 vials of starlight essence. He adds 47 more. How many vials does Storm have now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        344 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        172 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        132 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        86 vials
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many vials of starlight essence Storm has now, we need to add the number of vials he already has to the number of vials he adds. Storm starts with 125 vials and adds 47 more. First, we write the numbers down: 125 + 47 Now, we add the numbers together. We start by adding the ones place: 5 + 7 equals 12. We write down 2 and carry over 1. Next, we add the tens place: 2 + 4 equals 6, and then we add the 1 we carried over, which makes 7. Finally, we add the hundreds place: 1 + 0 equals 1. Putting it all together, we get 172. The answer is 172 vials.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 02:33:10 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        928
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      172 vials
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NF_3_NF_A_2_1749609130074" grade="3" domain="NF" standard="3.NF.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Finn has 3 potion recipes. Each recipe needs 2 dragon tears. How many dragon tears does Finn need for all recipes?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        9 dragon tears
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        12 dragon tears
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        6 dragon tears
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        11 dragon tears
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many dragon tears Finn needs for all his potion recipes, we start by looking at how many tears each recipe requires. Finn has 3 recipes, and each recipe needs 2 dragon tears. To find the total number of dragon tears needed, we can multiply the number of recipes by the number of tears each recipe needs. So, we calculate 3 (recipes) times 2 (dragon tears per recipe), which equals 6. Therefore, Finn needs a total of 6 dragon tears for all his recipes. The answer is 6 dragon tears.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 02:32:13 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        866
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      6 dragon tears
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NF_3_NF_A_3_1749609099417" grade="3" domain="NF" standard="3.NF.A.3" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Luna adds 1/4 cup of phoenix feathers to the cauldron. If she adds another 1/4 cup, how much is in the cauldron now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        1/2 cup
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        3/2 cup
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        2/2 cup
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        6/2 cup
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      Luna starts by adding 1/4 cup of phoenix feathers to the cauldron. Then, she adds another 1/4 cup. To find out how much is in the cauldron now, we need to add the two amounts together: 1/4 cup + 1/4 cup = 2/4 cup. Now, 2/4 cup can be simplified to 1/2 cup because 2 divided by 2 is 1 and 4 divided by 2 is 2. The answer is 1/2 cup.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 02:31:44 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        895
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      1/2 cup
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_A_2_1749609080993" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Felix collected 12 phoenix feathers. If he finds 5 more, how many phoenix feathers does he have now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        17 phoenix feathers
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        34 phoenix feathers
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        19 phoenix feathers
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        22 phoenix feathers
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many phoenix feathers Felix has now, we start with the number of feathers he already has, which is 12. Then, we add the 5 more feathers he finds. We can write this as a math problem: 12 (the feathers he has) + 5 (the feathers he finds) = 17. So, when we add 12 and 5 together, we get 17. The answer is 17 phoenix feathers.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 02:31:24 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        837
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      17 phoenix feathers
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_A_1_1749609007842" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Aurora has 5 crystal vials. She adds 12 more. How many crystal vials does she have now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        22 crystal vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        19 crystal vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        17 crystal vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        34 crystal vials
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many crystal vials Aurora has now, we start with the number of vials she already has, which is 5. Then, we need to add the 12 vials she adds to her collection. So, we can write the math like this: 5 (the vials she has) + 12 (the vials she adds) = 17. Now we see that when we add 5 and 12 together, we get 17. The answer is 17 crystal vials.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 02:30:12 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        858
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      17 crystal vials
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_C_7_1749608985700" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.C.7" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Briar has 5 elixir bottles. If she adds 3 more, how many elixir bottles does she have now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        13 elixir bottles
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        8 elixir bottles
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        16 elixir bottles
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        15 elixir bottles
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many elixir bottles Briar has now, we start with the number of bottles she already has, which is 5. Then, we add the 3 more bottles she is going to add. So, we can write the math like this: 5 (the bottles she has) + 3 (the bottles she adds) = 8. Now, we see that Briar has a total of 8 elixir bottles. The answer is 8 elixir bottles.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 02:29:48 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        856
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      8 elixir bottles
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_G_3_G_A_1_1749601657143" grade="3" domain="G" standard="3.G.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Thorek sees 4 bubbling poison pools. If he jumps over 3, how many pools remain?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        3 bubbling poison pool.
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        11 bubbling poison pool.
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        1 bubbling poison pool.
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        2 bubbling poison pool.
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To solve the problem, we start with 4 bubbling poison pools. Thorek jumps over 3 of them. We need to find out how many pools are left. We can do this by subtracting the number of pools Thorek jumped over from the total number of pools. So, we take 4 (the total pools) and subtract 3 (the pools he jumped over): 4 - 3 = 1. This means there is 1 bubbling poison pool remaining. The answer is 1 bubbling poison pool.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 00:27:40 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        897
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      1 bubbling poison pool.
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_B_4_1749601636565" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.B.4" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Zara collected 5 pixie dust vials each day for 8 days. How many vials did she collect in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        80 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        45 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        35 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        40 vials
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many pixie dust vials Zara collected in total, we need to multiply the number of vials she collected each day by the number of days she collected them. Zara collected 5 vials each day for 8 days. So, we can calculate this by doing the multiplication: 5 vials/day ร 8 days = 40 vials. This means Zara collected a total of 40 vials. The answer is 40 vials.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Wed Jun 11 2025 00:27:20 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        897
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      40 vials
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NBT_3_NBT_A_2_1749597442346" grade="3" domain="NBT" standard="3.NBT.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Storm collected 125 vials of starlight essence. If he uses 37 vials, how many vials remain?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        88 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        98 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        162 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        176 vials
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many vials of starlight essence Storm has left after using some, we need to subtract the number of vials he used from the total he collected. First, we start with the total number of vials, which is 125. Then, we subtract the 37 vials he used: 125 - 37 = 88. So, after using 37 vials, Storm has 88 vials remaining. The answer is 88 vials.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Tue Jun 10 2025 23:17:25 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        855
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      88 vials
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_C_5_1749597409711" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.C.5" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Vale collected 3 vials of fairy dust. Each vial contains 5 grams. How many grams of fairy dust does Vale have in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        15 grams
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        30 grams
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        20 grams
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        17 grams
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many grams of fairy dust Vale has in total, we need to multiply the number of vials by the amount of fairy dust in each vial. Vale has 3 vials, and each vial contains 5 grams of fairy dust. We can write this as a multiplication problem: 3 vials ร 5 grams per vial = 15 grams. So, Vale has a total of 15 grams of fairy dust. The answer is 15 grams.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Tue Jun 10 2025 23:16:53 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        847
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      15 grams
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_D_8_1749597276403" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.D.8" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Clover has 5 vials of phoenix feathers and 3 vials of unicorn horn. How many vials of spell ingredients does she have in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        13 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        16 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        15 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        8 vials
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many vials of spell ingredients Clover has in total, we need to add the number of vials of phoenix feathers to the number of vials of unicorn horn. Clover has 5 vials of phoenix feathers and 3 vials of unicorn horn. We can write this as a math problem: 5 (phoenix feathers) + 3 (unicorn horn) = 8 (total vials). So, when we add 5 and 3 together, we get 8. The answer is 8 vials.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Tue Jun 10 2025 23:14:38 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        870
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      8 vials
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_A_2_1749597262509" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Felix collected 5 phoenix feathers. If he finds 3 more, how many feathers does he have in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        13 feathers
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        16 feathers
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        8 feathers
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        15 feathers
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many feathers Felix has in total, we start with the number of feathers he already has, which is 5. Then, we need to add the 3 more feathers he finds. We can write this as a math problem: 5 + 3. When we add these numbers together, we get 8. So, Felix has a total of 8 feathers now. The answer is 8 feathers.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Tue Jun 10 2025 23:14:26 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        827
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      8 feathers
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_A_1_1749597260008" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Aurora has 5 crystal vials. She brews 3 potions in each vial. How many potions does she have in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        30 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        20 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        17 potions
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        15 potions
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many potions Aurora has in total, we need to multiply the number of vials by the number of potions in each vial. Aurora has 5 vials and brews 3 potions in each one. So, we can do the math like this: 5 vials ร 3 potions per vial = 15 potions. This means that Aurora has a total of 15 potions. The answer is 15 potions.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Tue Jun 10 2025 23:14:22 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        852
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      15 potions
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_G_3_G_A_1_1749597240329" grade="3" domain="G" standard="3.G.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Ember has 8 vials of mystic powders. If she adds 5 more, how many vials does she have in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        26 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        13 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        15 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        18 vials
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many vials of mystic powders Ember has in total, we start with the number of vials she already has, which is 8. Then, we add the 5 more vials she is going to add. We can write this as a math equation: 8 + 5 = 13. So, when we add 8 and 5 together, we get 13. The answer is 13 vials.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Tue Jun 10 2025 23:14:05 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        843
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      13 vials
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_C_7_1749597224257" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.C.7" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Briar has 5 elixir bottles. She buys 7 more. How many elixir bottles does Briar have now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        14 elixir bottles
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        12 elixir bottles
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        24 elixir bottles
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        17 elixir bottles
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many elixir bottles Briar has now, we start with the number of bottles she already has, which is 5. Then, we add the 7 more bottles she bought. So, we can write the math like this: 5 (the bottles she has) + 7 (the bottles she buys) = 12. Now we see that Briar has a total of 12 elixir bottles. The answer is 12 elixir bottles.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Tue Jun 10 2025 23:13:48 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        851
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      12 elixir bottles
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NF_3_NF_A_2_1749597153903" grade="3" domain="NF" standard="3.NF.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Finn has 3 potion recipes. Each recipe needs 2 ingredients. How many total ingredients does Finn need for all recipes?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        8 ingredients
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        6 ingredients
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        12 ingredients
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        11 ingredients
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many total ingredients Finn needs for all his potion recipes, we can use multiplication. Finn has 3 recipes, and each recipe needs 2 ingredients. We can multiply the number of recipes by the number of ingredients per recipe: 3 recipes ร 2 ingredients = 6 ingredients. So, Finn needs a total of 6 ingredients for all his recipes. The answer is 6 ingredients.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Tue Jun 10 2025 23:12:37 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        827
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      6 ingredients
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NF_3_NF_A_3_1749597134243" grade="3" domain="NF" standard="3.NF.A.3" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Luna adds 1/4 potion to the cauldron. If she adds 3 more 1/4 potions, how much potion is in the cauldron now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        9 whole potion
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        2 whole potion
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        3 whole potion
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        1 whole potion
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      Luna starts by adding 1/4 of a potion to the cauldron. Then, she adds 3 more 1/4 potions. To find out how much potion she has in total, we can add these fractions together: 1/4 + 1/4 + 1/4 + 1/4 = 4/4. When we add 4/4, it equals 1 whole potion. The answer is 1 whole potion.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Tue Jun 10 2025 23:12:17 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        875
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      1 whole potion
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_B_4_1749596252707" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.B.4" tier="1">
    <stem>
      River has 5 toy potions. Each potion needs 4 drops. How many drops does River need for all potions?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        20 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        40 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        25 drops
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        22 drops
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many drops River needs for all of her potions, we can use multiplication. River has 5 toy potions, and each potion needs 4 drops. We can multiply the number of potions by the number of drops each potion needs: 5 potions ร 4 drops = 20 drops. So, River needs a total of 20 drops for all her potions. The answer is 20 drops.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Tue Jun 10 2025 22:57:36 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        561
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      20 drops
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_A_2_1749596181108" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Drew has 15 coins. He buys a potion for 7 coins. How many coins does he have left?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        16 coins
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        13 coins
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        10 coins
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        8 coins
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many coins Drew has left after buying the potion, we start with the number of coins he originally has, which is 15 coins. Then, we need to subtract the number of coins he spent on the potion, which is 7 coins. So, we do the math: 15 coins - 7 coins = 8 coins. This means Drew has 8 coins left after his purchase. The answer is 8 coins.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Tue Jun 10 2025 22:56:23 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        558
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      8 coins
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_A_1_1749596163003" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Emery has 5 potion books. Alex gives her 3 more. How many potion books does Emery have now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        8 books
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        16 books
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        15 books
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        13 books
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many potion books Emery has now, we start with the number of books she already has, which is 5. Then, we add the 3 more books that Alex gives her. So, we do the math: 5 (the books Emery has) + 3 (the books Alex gives her) = 8. Now, Emery has a total of 8 potion books. The answer is 8 books.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Tue Jun 10 2025 22:56:06 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        556
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      8 books
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_C_6_1749596136779" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.C.6" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Phoenix has 42 potion-making cards. If he gives Morgan 14 cards, how many cards does Phoenix have left?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        33 cards
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        28 cards
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        38 cards
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        56 cards
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many potion-making cards Phoenix has left after giving some to Morgan, we start with the number of cards he originally has, which is 42. Then, we need to subtract the number of cards he gives away, which is 14. So, we do the math like this: 42 (original cards) - 14 (cards given to Morgan) = 28 cards left. Therefore, after giving away 14 cards, Phoenix has 28 cards remaining. The answer is 28 cards.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Tue Jun 10 2025 22:55:39 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        572
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      28 cards
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_D_8_1749596103836" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.D.8" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Nova picked 12 flowers. She used 5 for a potion. How many flowers does she have left?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        9 flowers
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        12 flowers
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        7 flowers
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        14 flowers
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many flowers Nova has left, we start with the total number of flowers she picked, which is 12. Then, we need to subtract the number of flowers she used for the potion, which is 5. So, we do the math: 12 (total flowers) - 5 (flowers used) = 7 (flowers left). Therefore, Nova has 7 flowers remaining. The answer is 7 flowers.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Tue Jun 10 2025 22:55:07 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        554
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      7 flowers
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_D_8_1749595768607" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.D.8" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Bombur has 5 miruvor vials. Boromir gives him 3 more. How many miruvor vials does Bombur have now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        8 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        13 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        15 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        16 vials
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many miruvor vials Bombur has now, we start with the number of vials he already has, which is 5. Then, we add the 3 vials that Boromir gives him. So, we do the math like this: 5 vials + 3 vials = 8 vials. Now, we can see that Bombur has a total of 8 miruvor vials. The answer is 8 vials.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Tue Jun 10 2025 22:49:32 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        868
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      8 vials
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_D_8_1749595243459" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.D.8" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Bombur collects 12 miruvor vials. If he finds 8 more, how many vials does he have in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        25 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        22 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        40 vials
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        20 vials
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many miruvor vials Bombur has in total, we start with the number of vials he already has, which is 12. Then, we add the 8 more vials he finds. We can write this as a math problem: 12 (the vials he has) + 8 (the vials he finds) = 20. So, when we add 12 and 8 together, we get 20. The answer is 20 vials.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Tue Jun 10 2025 22:40:47 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        861
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      20 vials
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_3_MD_A_1_1749591966803" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Emery brewed 5 magic potions. Each potion needs 3 ingredients. How many ingredients did Emery use in total?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        15 ingredients
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        17 ingredients
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        30 ingredients
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        20 ingredients
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many ingredients Emery used in total, we need to multiply the number of potions by the number of ingredients in each potion. Emery brewed 5 potions, and each potion needs 3 ingredients. So, we can write the math like this: 5 potions ร 3 ingredients = 15 ingredients. This means Emery used a total of 15 ingredients for all the potions. The answer is 15 ingredients.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Tue Jun 10 2025 21:46:10 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        584
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      15 ingredients
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_G_3_G_A_1_1749591867382" grade="3" domain="G" standard="3.G.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Rowan found 8 phoenix feathers. Zara gave him 5 more. How many phoenix feathers does Rowan have now?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        26 feathers
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        18 feathers
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        13 feathers
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        15 feathers
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many phoenix feathers Rowan has now, we start with the number of feathers he originally found, which is 8. Then, we add the 5 feathers that Zara gave him. So, we can write the math like this: 8 (the feathers Rowan found) + 5 (the feathers Zara gave him) = 13. Now, we see that Rowan has a total of 13 phoenix feathers. The answer is 13 feathers.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Tue Jun 10 2025 21:44:30 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        583
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      13 feathers
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NF_3_NF_A_2_1749591773256" grade="3" domain="NF" standard="3.NF.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Jordan brewed 3 magic potions. Each potion needs 1/4 cup of dragon's blood. How much dragon's blood is needed for all potions?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        5/4 cup
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        6/4 cup
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        3/4 cup
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        4/4 cup
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how much dragon's blood Jordan needs for all three potions, we start by looking at how much each potion requires. Each potion needs 1/4 cup of dragon's blood. Since there are 3 potions, we can add the amount needed for each one together. We can write this as: 1/4 cup + 1/4 cup + 1/4 cup. When we add these fractions, we keep the same denominator (which is 4) and add the numerators (the top numbers): 1 + 1 + 1 = 3. So, we have 3/4 cup of dragon's blood in total. The answer is 3/4 cup.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Tue Jun 10 2025 21:42:57 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        665
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      3/4 cup
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_NBT_3_NBT_A_3_1749591749407" grade="3" domain="NBT" standard="3.NBT.A.3" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Felix found 47 phoenix feathers. If he gives Sage 12 feathers, how many does Felix have left?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        70 feathers
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        45 feathers
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        59 feathers
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        35 feathers
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how many feathers Felix has left after giving some to Sage, we start with the number of feathers he originally has, which is 47. Then, we need to subtract the 12 feathers he gives to Sage. So, we do the math: 47 - 12 = 35. This means that after giving away 12 feathers, Felix has 35 feathers left. The answer is 35 feathers.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Tue Jun 10 2025 21:42:33 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        581
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      35 feathers
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_G_3_G_A_1_1749444256205" grade="3" domain="G" standard="3.G.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Kai drew a triangle with sides measuring 5 cm, 7 cm, and 9 cm. What type of triangle did he draw?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        3
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        Scalene triangle
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        1
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        2
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To determine what type of triangle Kai drew, we need to look at the lengths of its sides. The sides of the triangle measure 5 cm, 7 cm, and 9 cm. A scalene triangle is a triangle where all three sides are different lengths. Since 5 cm, 7 cm, and 9 cm are all different, we can say that Kai drew a scalene triangle. The answer is Scalene triangle.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Mon Jun 09 2025 04:44:18 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        554
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      Scalene triangle
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_G_3_G_A_2_1749325320247" grade="3" domain="G" standard="3.G.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Quinn and Phoenix are at the beach collecting shells. Quinn finds a large shell that is shaped like a triangle, and its sides measure 4 inches, 5 inches, and 6 inches. Phoenix finds a shell that is shaped like a square with each side measuring 4 inches. How many more inches around is the perimeter of Quinn's triangular shell compared to Phoenix's square shell?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        The perimeter of Quinn's triangular shell is 20 inches (4 + 5 + 6 = 20), and the perimeter of Phoenix's square shell is 16 inches (4 + 4 + 4 + 4 = 16). So, the difference is 1 inch (16 - 20 = 1).
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        The perimeter of Quinn's triangular shell is 17 inches (4 + 5 + 6 = 17), and the perimeter of Phoenix's square shell is 16 inches (4 + 4 + 4 + 4 = 16). So, the difference is 1 inch (16 - 17 = 1).
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        The perimeter of Quinn's triangular shell is 15 inches (4 + 5 + 6 = 15), and the perimeter of Phoenix's square shell is 16 inches (4 + 4 + 4 + 4 = 16). So, the difference is 1 inch (16 - 15 = 1).
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        The perimeter of Quinn's triangular shell is 30 inches (4 + 5 + 6 = 30), and the perimeter of Phoenix's square shell is 16 inches (4 + 4 + 4 + 4 = 16). So, the difference is 1 inch (16 - 30 = 1).
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      Let's find out how much more Quinn's triangular shell's perimeter is compared to Phoenix's square shell! 

First, we add up the sides of Quinn's triangle: 4 inches + 5 inches + 6 inches = 15 inches. This is the perimeter of Quinn's shell. 

Next, we add up the sides of Phoenix's square: 4 inches + 4 inches + 4 inches + 4 inches = 16 inches. This is the perimeter of Phoenix's shell. 

Now, we subtract Quinn's perimeter from Phoenix's: 16 inches - 15 inches = 1 inch. So, Phoenix's shell is 1 inch more around than Quinn's shell! Great job figuring that out!
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Sat Jun 07 2025 19:42:07 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        690
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      The perimeter of Quinn's triangular shell is 15 inches (4 + 5 + 6 = 15), and the perimeter of Phoenix's square shell is 16 inches (4 + 4 + 4 + 4 = 16). So, the difference is 1 inch (16 - 15 = 1).
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_G_G_A_54024264_qwtr" grade="3" domain="G" standard="3.G.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      What is the perimeter of a rectangle with a length of 5 units and a width of 3 units? (Use the formula: Perimeter = 2 ร (length + width))
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        32 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        16 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        21 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        20 units
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find the perimeter of a rectangle, we use the formula: Perimeter = 2 ร (length + width). For our rectangle, the length is 5 units and the width is 3 units. So, we add 5 and 3 to get 8, and then multiply by 2, which gives us 16 units for the perimeter!
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Fri Jun 06 2025 23:53:50 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        188
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      16 units
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_G_G_A_51765220_0tbl" grade="3" domain="G" standard="3.G.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      In a colorful art class, Lucas, who loves painting landscapes, created a rectangular canvas that is 4 feet long and 3 feet wide. His friend Amina, who enjoys painting abstract designs, made a square canvas that has sides measuring 2 feet. How much larger is the area of Lucas's rectangular canvas compared to Amina's square canvas?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        12 square feet
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        20 square feet
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        15 square feet
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        10 square feet
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out how much larger Lucas's canvas is compared to Amina's, we first need to calculate the area of each canvas. 

1. **Lucas's rectangular canvas**: The area is found by multiplying the length by the width. So, 4 feet (length) ร 3 feet (width) = 12 square feet.
  
2. **Amina's square canvas**: The area is found by multiplying the side by itself. So, 2 feet (side) ร 2 feet (side) = 4 square feet.

Now, we subtract Amina's area from Lucas's area: 12 square feet - 4 square feet = 8 square feet. 

Oops! It seems there was a mistake in the original answer. The correct difference in area is actually 8 square feet, not 10.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Fri Jun 06 2025 23:16:12 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        320
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      10 square feet
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_G_G_A_45460466_h0kc" grade="3" domain="G" standard="3.G.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      What is the perimeter of a rectangle with a length of 5 units and a width of 3 units? (Use the formula: Perimeter = 2 ร (length + width))
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        16 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        32 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        20 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        21 units
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find the perimeter of a rectangle, we use the formula: Perimeter = 2 ร (length + width). Here, the length is 5 units and the width is 3 units. So, we first add 5 and 3 to get 8, and then we multiply by 2, which gives us 16 units for the perimeter. This means if you walked all the way around the rectangle, you would travel 16 units!
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Fri Jun 06 2025 21:31:06 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        207
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      16 units
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_G_G_A_35226016_4bws" grade="3" domain="G" standard="3.G.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      What is the area of a rectangle that has a length of 5 units and a width of 3 units? (Use the formula: Area = Length ร Width)
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        30 square units
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        15 square units
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        17 square units
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        20 square units
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find the area of a rectangle, we use the formula: Area = Length ร Width. In this case, the length is 5 units and the width is 3 units. So, we multiply 5 by 3, which gives us 15. Therefore, the area of the rectangle is 15 square units! This means if you filled the rectangle with 1-unit squares, you could fit 15 of them inside.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Fri Jun 06 2025 18:40:32 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        200
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      15 square units
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_G_G_A_35200391_6gip" grade="3" domain="G" standard="3.G.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      What is the perimeter of a rectangle with a length of 5 units and a width of 3 units? (Use the formula: Perimeter = 2 ร (length + width))
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        21 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        20 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        16 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        32 units
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find the perimeter of a rectangle, we use the formula: Perimeter = 2 ร (length + width). In this case, the length is 5 units and the width is 3 units. So, we first add the length and width together: 5 + 3 = 8. Then, we multiply that sum by 2: 2 ร 8 = 16. Therefore, the perimeter of the rectangle is 16 units!
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Fri Jun 06 2025 18:40:07 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        208
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      16 units
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_G_G_A_33504821_rlnb" grade="3" domain="G" standard="3.G.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      What is the perimeter of a rectangle with a length of 5 units and a width of 3 units? (Use the formula: Perimeter = 2 ร (length + width))
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        16 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        32 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        20 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        21 units
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find the perimeter of a rectangle, we can use the formula: Perimeter = 2 ร (length + width). Here, the length is 5 units and the width is 3 units. So, we first add the length and width together: 5 + 3 = 8. Then, we multiply that sum by 2: 2 ร 8 = 16. Therefore, the perimeter of the rectangle is 16 units!
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Fri Jun 06 2025 18:11:53 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        207
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      16 units
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_G_G_A_31948299_00er" grade="3" domain="G" standard="3.G.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      What is the perimeter of a rectangle with a length of 5 units and a width of 3 units? (Use the formula: Perimeter = 2 ร (length + width))
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        32 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        21 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        20 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        16 units
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find the perimeter of a rectangle, we use the formula: Perimeter = 2 ร (length + width). Here, the length is 5 units and the width is 3 units. First, we add the length and width together: 5 + 3 = 8. Then, we multiply that sum by 2: 2 ร 8 = 16. So, the perimeter of the rectangle is 16 units!
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Fri Jun 06 2025 17:45:54 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        205
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      16 units
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_G_G_A_30622950_2oi3" grade="3" domain="G" standard="3.G.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      What is the perimeter of a rectangle with a length of 5 units and a width of 3 units? (Use the formula: Perimeter = 2 ร (length + width))
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        32 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        21 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        16 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        20 units
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find the perimeter of a rectangle, we use the formula: Perimeter = 2 ร (length + width). For our rectangle, the length is 5 units and the width is 3 units. So, we first add the length and width together: 5 + 3 = 8. Then, we multiply that sum by 2: 2 ร 8 = 16. Therefore, the perimeter of the rectangle is 16 units!
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Fri Jun 06 2025 17:23:50 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        208
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      16 units
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_G_G_A_28289446_hqef" grade="3" domain="G" standard="3.G.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      What is the perimeter of a rectangle with a length of 5 units and a width of 3 units? (Use the formula: Perimeter = 2 ร (length + width))
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        21 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        32 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        20 units
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        16 units
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find the perimeter of a rectangle, we use the formula: Perimeter = 2 ร (length + width). For our rectangle, the length is 5 units and the width is 3 units. So, we first add the length and width together: 5 + 3 = 8. Then, we multiply that sum by 2: 2 ร 8 = 16. Therefore, the perimeter of the rectangle is 16 units!
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Fri Jun 06 2025 16:44:56 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        208
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      16 units
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_G_G_A_97559334_zqpf" grade="3" domain="G" standard="3.G.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Juno and Finn are building a garden in their backyard. Juno wants to create a rectangular flower bed that is 4 feet long and 3 feet wide. Finn wants to create a square vegetable patch that has sides measuring 3 feet. What is the area of Juno's flower bed compared to the area of Finn's vegetable patch?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        Juno's flower bed has an area of 12 square feet, while Finn's vegetable patch has an area of 9 square feet.
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        Juno's flower bed has an area of 24 square feet, while Finn's vegetable patch has an area of 9 square feet.
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        Juno's flower bed has an area of 14 square feet, while Finn's vegetable patch has an area of 9 square feet.
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        Juno's flower bed has an area of 17 square feet, while Finn's vegetable patch has an area of 9 square feet.
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find the area of Juno's flower bed, we multiply the length (4 feet) by the width (3 feet), which gives us 4 x 3 = 12 square feet. For Finn's vegetable patch, since it's a square, we multiply one side (3 feet) by itself, which gives us 3 x 3 = 9 square feet. So, Juno's flower bed is larger with an area of 12 square feet compared to Finn's 9 square feet!
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Fri Jun 06 2025 08:12:44 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        272
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="A">
      Juno's flower bed has an area of 12 square feet, while Finn's vegetable patch has an area of 9 square feet.
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_G_G_A_97214613_2280" grade="3" domain="G" standard="3.G.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Alex and Yasmin are creating a colorful mural for their school's art show. Alex paints a rectangle that is 4 feet long and 3 feet wide, while Yasmin paints a square that has sides measuring 3 feet each. What is the area of the mural that Alex painted compared to the area of the mural that Yasmin painted?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        Option 2
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        Option 3
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        Option 4
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        The area of Alex's mural is larger.
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find the area of Alex's rectangle, we multiply the length by the width: 4 feet ร 3 feet = 12 square feet. For Yasmin's square, we multiply the side by itself: 3 feet ร 3 feet = 9 square feet. Since 12 square feet (Alex's mural) is greater than 9 square feet (Yasmin's mural), Alex's mural is larger!
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Fri Jun 06 2025 08:07:00 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        236
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      The area of Alex's mural is larger.
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_G_G_A_96693217_0tz8" grade="3" domain="G" standard="3.G.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Carlos and Elena are creating art for their school's cultural festival. Carlos makes a rectangular painting that is 4 feet wide and 6 feet long. Elena makes a square painting with each side measuring 5 feet. What is the area of Carlos's painting compared to the area of Elena's painting?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        Carlos's painting has an area of 29 square feet, and Elena's painting has an area of 25 square feet.
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        Carlos's painting has an area of 48 square feet, and Elena's painting has an area of 25 square feet.
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        Carlos's painting has an area of 24 square feet, and Elena's painting has an area of 25 square feet.
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        Carlos's painting has an area of 28 square feet, and Elena's painting has an area of 25 square feet.
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find the area of Carlos's rectangular painting, we multiply the width by the length: 4 feet ร 6 feet = 24 square feet. For Elena's square painting, we multiply the length of one side by itself: 5 feet ร 5 feet = 25 square feet. So, Carlos's painting is 24 square feet, and Elena's painting is 25 square feet, which means Elena's painting is a little bigger!
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Fri Jun 06 2025 07:58:19 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        248
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="C">
      Carlos's painting has an area of 24 square feet, and Elena's painting has an area of 25 square feet.
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_MD_A_95610700_rlka" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      In a classroom, Aria and Noah are measuring the lengths of their art projects. Aria's project is 3/4 of a meter long while Noah's project is 2/3 of a meter long. Which project is longer?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        Option 3
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        Aria's project is longer.
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        Option 2
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        Option 4
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find out which project is longer, we need to compare the two fractions: 3/4 and 2/3. First, we can think of both fractions in terms of the same size pieces. If we convert them to have a common denominator, we can see that 3/4 is equal to 9/12 and 2/3 is equal to 8/12. Since 9/12 is greater than 8/12, Aria's project is longer than Noah's project!
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Fri Jun 06 2025 07:40:16 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        231
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      Aria's project is longer.
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_G_G_A_95579049_2yae" grade="3" domain="G" standard="3.G.A.1" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Elena and Carlos are creating a mural for their school. Elena painted a rectangle that is 4 feet long and 3 feet wide, while Carlos painted a square that has sides measuring 3 feet. What is the area of the rectangle painted by Elena compared to the area of the square painted by Carlos?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        Option 4
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        Option 2
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        Option 3
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        The area of the rectangle is larger.
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      To find the area of Elena's rectangle, we multiply the length by the width: 4 feet (length) ร 3 feet (width) = 12 square feet. For Carlos's square, we multiply the length of one side by itself: 3 feet ร 3 feet = 9 square feet. Since 12 square feet (Elena's rectangle) is more than 9 square feet (Carlos's square), the area of the rectangle is larger!
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Fri Jun 06 2025 07:39:46 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        237
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="D">
      The area of the rectangle is larger.
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="G3_MD_MD_A_84147634_k9o1" grade="3" domain="MD" standard="3.MD.A.2" tier="1">
    <stem>
      Fatima has 5 pencils, each measuring 7 inches long. How many inches long are all her pencils if she lines them up end to end?
    </stem>
    <choices>
      <choice id="A">
        40
      </choice>
      <choice id="B">
        36
      </choice>
      <choice id="C">
        72
      </choice>
      <choice id="D">
        41
      </choice>
    </choices>
    <explanation>
      Multiply 5 pencils ร 7 inches each to find the total length. Great job! The answer is 36.
    </explanation>
    <metadata>
      <created>
        Fri Jun 06 2025 04:29:11 GMT+0000 (Coordinated Universal Time)
      </created>
      <tokens_used>
        542
      </tokens_used>
    </metadata>
    <answer key="B">
      36
    </answer>
  </question>
</questions>